PAUL: Yeah, hello everyone, am I audible? Please let me know in the chats.
PAUL: And just check the charts are opened or not.
PAUL: Weird.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, looks like a few people have not joined yet.
PAUL: All right, everyone, good morning.
PAUL: Alright, so in the meantime, let's discuss a few things.
PAUL: Just okay. Let's start.
PAUL: So today, I think everybody knows about today's agenda. We'll be continuing with Llama parts.
PAUL: Okay, and let's see, like, how much we can cover today. Okay, so let me start sharing my screen.
PAUL: This is install 3… okay.
PAUL: Is there anyone who had joined the class for the first time? They can let me know in the chat.
PAUL: Then I'll be sharing the Notion link, otherwise we will continue.
PAUL: Okay, so this week's agenda, so, like, few things have changed, so let's talk about them.
PAUL: Think, where is my set?
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So, I think everyone of you can see. So, previously in the last class, in the last week, we have discussed about dockling and unstructured. Okay, so two different types of data paths, and finally today, we'll be talking with respect to LAMA paths.
PAUL: Klamapars is a paid service, basically. Okay, in the last session, I hope everybody has done the installation. We have spent some time with respect to the installation, so I think that by this time, you guys have resolved most of the issues that you were facing.
PAUL: No,
PAUL: So, very specifically, there was another password that I kept, which was Vectorize, but right now, Vectorize has totally removed
PAUL: API access for free plans. Okay, so the idea is that, three parsers we have already discussed, so vectorized, probably, you can skip, because it is less famous as compared to these three very specifically.
PAUL: But if you want, okay, I'll be sharing that vectorized content, because I think you need to pay close to $99, okay, to get to the service, and then only you can actually use the AI, okay? So, just a little bit, because I think the last month it was there, but finally, like,
PAUL: In the last month, the update came, so the free API access has been removed.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, today, Lama passed, and then probably going forward, like, tomorrow, let's see, we will start with the first project that we have.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Right now, Rahul, is asking recap from the last session. In the last session, those were much more about the frameworks, nothing so much conceptual, that giving a recap. If I start giving a recap again, the entire notebook will take a lot of time.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, with respect to the project, let me talk about…
PAUL: Okay, so I think I have my… Gitout…
PAUL: Let me just open my GitHub once, just wait.
PAUL: No, no, it's not like an assignment, this is…
PAUL: Actually, the project that you have.
PAUL: Alright, now let me just share you the GitHub part. Okay, so generally, most of the things can be tracked through GitHub. Okay, so I have kept majorly all of your projects here only. So, if you go to the repo, okay, and I think this is…
PAUL: the one right now, the RAC UN project.
PAUL: Okay, so this will be the main project that we'll be discussing in the meantime in training videos. So, till now, this is under development. I have added a lot of stuff, but
PAUL: The idea is that initially, a lot of things are there that we'll be talking about.
PAUL: Okay, so in the meantime, with respect to the setup and other stuff, very specifically, if you want… okay, so that's why I'm letting you know before, so that on the day of the project, okay, like, if I'm starting it tomorrow, okay, there should not be at least any type of installation issues.
PAUL: Okay, so just be sure that you have work with respect to the environment creation part, the most important thing.
PAUL: Because if you're stuck at the installation phase, okay, it will be a problem.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, alright, I'll be sharing the link of the project.
PAUL: Okay, so it has a lot of different things that I have added, but for now, majorly,
PAUL: The core idea is at least be sure that your environment is ready. That is the bare minimum, okay?
PAUL: I hope everybody understands.
PAUL: Okay, because this will be the most simple, the core idea is that building that full-fledged application, that part I have taken much more important, because I think the core implementation is very similar to Lanshan Notebook 7.
PAUL: Okay, that exactly LCL, call, everything, so that RAG is name RAG, but building that entire thing… okay, so there I am actually focused, and for CICD,
PAUL: CI part, GitHub Actions, very specifically, I have used. And for the delivery part, I have used AWS AppRunner, okay?
PAUL: Okay, and others, like, going forward, what are the projects that I'll be discussing? Okay, so few things. So, you can always look into my reports if you don't ask about me. Okay, so the multidata project, which is… which will be your
PAUL: two projects. That part also, right now, I'm working, but this will be basically a second project. Here, I have added SQL also. Okay, like, text to SQL, so that particular thing using VANA, okay.
PAUL: So, this also I have added it. So, you can have a look, okay, once you look into my reports. Very specifically for the projects, I think I have added it.
PAUL: Alright, so today's… and finally, this will be your third project, I think, which is the hybrid search. Then you have a multimodal rack project. Okay, so type… hybrid search is… will be the toughest project in your course, just remember that.
PAUL: Okay, now this will be the toughest one, it…
PAUL: will take time, for sure, but really… okay, so this one, fees-wise, as I was dividing it, so this will take a lot of time for me. It has, like… very specifically, I'm using Cates also here, that's why Kubernetes, because of that.
PAUL: And entirely.
PAUL: Alright, in AWS, there is no such installation that I need help, only that AWS CLI part, I think you guys need to do, okay? So, like, for future projects, like, this is in development, so, like, if you take a fork, the idea is that please keep a fork in your repo, and whenever I'm doing any type of commits, place.
PAUL: Update it, okay?
PAUL: Yes, we'll be having session on 27th and 28th.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Only 31st and 1st January, if any batches are there, they will be canceled.
PAUL: All right, so prerequisites, don't worry, this will be probably in the month of February. Okay, so, initial project, I think everybody, the core idea is that, many people who are not coming from Python background.
PAUL: okay, a little bit of problem will be there, but the idea is that after the classes, at least go and explore a few topics, like working with FastAPI, or at least with Flask.
PAUL: Okay, because my major stack, everybody can look into, okay?
PAUL: And, going forward, one of the projects that I'll be looking for, where I'll be looking for contributors very specifically, okay, so whoever is interested, so based on that, so we can build some things.
PAUL: But it will be much more individual contributions, because directly I'll be looking for if anybody has
PAUL: Weekly, like, 6 to 8 hours that you guys can commit.
PAUL: Okay, and for everything, it's not like you write it from scratch, rather than… you can use wild coding, I have no issues, but at least you should be familiar with those things.
PAUL: Alright, so majorly this part, okay, so project part, I have already shared with you the things that I'll be doing. And, one important thing, see, right now, with respect to test cases, I have kept it, in the first project, not a lot of test cases, but poorly with respect to simple Pythonic test cases.
PAUL: Like, linting, rough, formatting, those type of things, okay? So, I'll be talking about those stuff, but for now, just explore the rib. Okay, that's the core idea. Once we start our discussion, then usually most of the things will be done.
PAUL: Okay, alright, already shared the link.
PAUL: Okay, so I think…
PAUL: Open, can I get it free? No, I don't think Pavani will be getting it for free.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start with our… today's discussion. I think for everybody, the agenda is clear. I'm just sharing the content that I'm going to discuss in future, okay, and there will be updates, so just be sure you are…
PAUL: Just keep this particular option on whenever you take a work, like this watch.
PAUL: Okay, watch is very important.
PAUL: The idea is that if I'm doing any type of… the core idea will be looking into commits. What are the things that I have done? Okay, so majorly with respect to formatting, so always do look into my commits.
PAUL: Because bigger projects will have issues going forward, and really, like, these are big, big projects. It's not only that, but that entire Python ecosystem that we'll be talking about.
PAUL: No, R, I'm not going to show you, like, what's my way.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all, with respect to Lana, I think everybody has the content in the last class I have shared. Please let me know.
PAUL: Yes, please let me know, guys. I think where is that data parsers? Data parsers.
PAUL: Data park.
PAUL: Okay, I think I have shared it somewhere.
PAUL: Can you please reshare again already, just let me open motion, okay?
PAUL: In motion, you have that… TikTok processes.
PAUL: Alright, so this is the repo.
PAUL: I have just a few minor updates that I have done.
PAUL: Okay, so everybody please take a clone of this one.
PAUL: No, little bit, I think some updates that I have done.
PAUL: Okay, so everybody just take a clone. That's the idea.
PAUL: We are doable, no issue.
PAUL: Specific Python frameworks? Frameworks with respect to, I will say, past API is one of the most important ones.
PAUL: Because, right now, majorly, my idea will be building back-ends, rather than front-ends. I hope that should be the priority for anyone. Okay, so for that…
PAUL: Though I was working on the UI a little bit, I think I created a branch, I'm working on that, but again, like, everything is not ready.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Parcels where I've already shared it. Please, everyone.
PAUL: do a git pull.
PAUL: Please let me know once you guys are ready, because you can use the same environment in the last class that you have done the installation with, because with respect to the installation in the last class you have already gone through.
PAUL: In the meantime, let me just open the official documentation of Llama.
PAUL: Please let me know, guys.
PAUL: Everyone ready in the last plaza, I hope the installation is done.
PAUL: Okay? Ready? Everyone, please let me know with a thumbs up, then we'll start.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So, right now, majorly, the…
PAUL: I can say the framework that we have discussed, Unstructured and Dockling, they do have an open source version. Okay, Dockling is totally open source from IBM, very specifically. Similarly, Unstructured, they do have,
PAUL: a specific enterprise edition also, okay? Now, two frameworks with respect to free stuff that we have already looked into.
PAUL: Now, the idea is look into something paid, the proprietary take, okay, from Llama. And very specifically, right now, the Llama Cloud is growing.
PAUL: Okay, a lot of new features that are coming very specifically with respect to parsing, extraction, working with sheets, working with videos, different type of things are coming. They are in beta, but the most robust service that they have is the parse one.
PAUL: So, we'll be talking with respect to parsing.
PAUL: First of all, Here, if you look into the official documentation, everything I have taken from the official documentation.
PAUL: Okay, so transforming your unstructured documents into LLM-ready data.
PAUL: Okay, and they have provided you some samples, okay? Now, somebody's asking about Llama Index versus Llama parts. Llama Index is much more of a GenAI framework. Using Lama Index, you can build a rag. Just similarly, you can think about all the features which are available in Langchain are available in Llama Index, okay?
PAUL: So, like, both do the same stuff. It's just like Keras and PyTorch in deep learning. Both… the same task can be achieved by both of the frameworks. So, similarly, like, LandChain, we have already discussed, after Llama Parse, I think after your project, there will be a specific part with respect to Llama Index also.
PAUL: Where we'll be talking about building RADs.
PAUL: But for now, today's agenda is very specifically with respect to LAMA parse. Okay, as we are discussing parcels for now.
PAUL: Okay, so now this is a paid product, so I think everybody has…
PAUL: got the API. In the last class, I have already showed you that part, so I think everybody is ready with that.
PAUL: Yes, everyone has the API?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Alright, fine, you guys have the API.
PAUL: Alright. If you guys have missed it, just simply open, Llama Cloud, I think.
PAUL: And do a sign-up.
PAUL: I don't think I have in this account, but… Go to, milama Cloud… I think… Llama Cloud API.
PAUL: Okay, yeah, my index.ti, and here you have to do a sign-up, everyone. I'm just sharing the URL.
PAUL: to everyone. Whoever has not done it.
PAUL: Okay, I know a few people have done it, but few people have joined today, that's why.
PAUL: Please do a sign up, I don't think I have a Gmail account in this one.
PAUL: Otherwise, I will just quickly show you once.
PAUL: Okay, so just be sure if you create your account, and based on that, okay, so all these details that they are asking, are now just pass.
PAUL: Okay, let me do a sign-in.
PAUL: Okay, so once you have this… okay, so once you do the sign-up, you'll be getting these options, and very specifically.
PAUL: Right now, this is the part, API key, that you can see in the left-hand side bottom. You have to just click here, and you have to create your own key.
PAUL: Okay, as simple as that.
PAUL: So just do a sign up, click on API keys, click on generate new API key, and you will be done.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: So, let's get back, I think, in our… Discussion, alright.
PAUL: So, right now, if I talk about the features very specifically.
PAUL: The features are seen just like dockling a non-structure. You have to understand this is also a similar data parsing library.
PAUL: But it has some premium options, as you know that this is completely API-based. Okay, and yes, you do have daily limits, close to, I think, 1,000 pages that you can do the parsing.
PAUL: And I think that's quite a lot for the free trial. Okay, and going forward, I think in paid users, they have close to 7,000 pages, okay? Now…
PAUL: Very specifically, I think you guys have done the installation, so let's start with the core setup part. Okay, I will just get back to the notebook, and just be sure everybody that your import section is working fine. There should not be any issues with respect to the import section. So I will just increase the font.
PAUL: And right now, the idea was to only check Lama Cloud API, so I have checked it, and in my case, it's importing pretty much correct, no issues.
PAUL: Now, two libraries are there. One is Lama Parse.
PAUL: And the other one is Llama Cloud Services.
PAUL: moves, I can say the recent updates are coming, okay, because actually, from Llama Pars, -
PAUL: The Lama Parse module has been integrated within the Lama Cloud Services. So the actual, package in future, I feel that where majorly the updates will be coming, it will be Lama Cloud Services.
PAUL: For your future reference, I'm telling you that, yes, this will be your main
PAUL: package. For now, Llama Parse is working fine, but I feel going forward, it will be deprecated.
PAUL: And all of the major services will come into Llama Cloud Services.
PAUL: Alright, so for now, I'm using Llama Pass, but if you really change, so I have kept this option, okay, and right now, I will just try to enable it, and you can see that it is working fine, there is no issue. So, similar input, but in future, Llama Cloud services will be used much more.
PAUL: And right now, I'll be performing, asynchronous operations also. For that, I'm using Nest Asyncure package.
PAUL: Using Lama powers whenever you are…
PAUL: doing any type of data ingestion for your RAG pipelines. In that case, it supports asynchronous stuff, so right now, for executing it in Jupyter Notebook, I'm just using this particular package so that I can do a lot of async operations.
PAUL: Other than that, there is no important, I think, modules.
PAUL: Pretty much common ones, OS, JSON, async queue, typing, and PathL.
PAUL: Okay, so the first part, I will now, first of all, look into the sample documents. I think you all guys already have access to this, and what are the different type of files which are available. So, I have provided them in the last class. So, very similarly.
PAUL: Why not async? Somebody's asking, really? Like, why not synchronous? Because when you are performing a batch operation, you want to do multiple tasks parallel. Because of that, async is needed. In any programming language, async is pretty much a common standard.
PAUL: Now let's get back to our documentation once.
PAUL: So, first of all, let's look into what are the things that they are providing, first of all.
PAUL: I hope everybody has done the installation, they have the API key, and very specifically, as you can see in the official documentation, they are referring to Lama Cloud Services and not Llama parts.
PAUL: No.
PAUL: directly, you can use it from the CLI also, but for now, I'll be using much more the Python-ing version, or basically the Python support.
PAUL: For working with CLI, again, commands have been provided. It means that you don't need any code directly. Also, you can do it from the CLI, no issues.
PAUL: Now, this is much more that we are focused on, okay, where we'll be working a lot with Python scripts.
PAUL: Now, moving into more than we said, the most important part in this particular, Lama Pass.
PAUL: Modes. Very, very important. Whenever you are working with data parsing and the types of document that you have, you need to always look into the different modes, because based on that, as it is a paid service.
PAUL: Okay, your credits will be used.
PAUL: If you are going with something premium options, more credits will be used as compared to simple presets. So, right now, the first one, like, which is available, as you can see here… Okay, so few options that they are talking about, like high resolution OCR.
PAUL: At any point of time, if you're working with high-resolution OCR, your results will be better than adaptive long table. Okay, at any point of time, if there are images, tables, everything that you can extract from the document. So, it has a lot of features.
PAUL: The first one is the agentic approach that they refer, and again, they have an Agentic Plus. So right now, this Agentic… so majorly with documents where you have a lot of things. It can be charts, it can be graphs, it can be tables, it can be images.
PAUL: Everything that you can actually extract.
PAUL: So, pretty much, I can say multimodal parsing mechanisms which are available directly.
PAUL: Then you have Agentic Plus, again, so one… another level, I can say, were advanced layout detection that take place, and through that research paper, invoices, financial reports, everything that you can actually look into.
PAUL: So, you really need to look what type of parsing that you want to do, and very specifically for that, what will be the mood. I feel, whenever you are working in Llama Parse, Agent Tick+, this is a very costly solution. It means that more credits get exhausted.
PAUL: Agentic is fine. If you… you have to do the experiment. In Agentic, I feel it's good, but again, in some cases, if the document is really complex, having a very complex layout, you can think about 3-columar layout, where you have 3 different types of images, a lot of graphs.
PAUL: Then sometimes it might fail, so you might move into agentic plus-based modes.
PAUL: And then, you have very specific presets for different type of documents. Right now.
PAUL: only 3, I think 3 to 4 are supported. The invoices, if you're directly working with invoices. Then comes scientific papers, technical documentation. Okay, so directly, there is a preset option where you can pass it. So these things will be doing it in the
PAUL: Jupyter Notebook also, but for now, just have a look at least what are the main features which they are providing. Now, this particular support, there is, like, neither it is with Docklink, neither it is with unstructured. You have to understand. Now, this is very unique only with LamaPass.
PAUL: Where you can, use very specifically, I think 4 presets are available, the invoices, the scientific paper, the technical documentation, and forms.
PAUL: And I will say the results are very good if you try to compare it with
PAUL: some OCRB solutions, like, which are really good in the market, like Azure Document Intelligence. So, the results are very, very close, so I feel that, it works really good here.
PAUL: Now, looking into some advanced parsing modes, okay? Now, parsing modes is very specifically for enabling your parsers.
PAUL: the different type of parse mode that it has, we'll be talking about. So, the first one is, like, without AI. If you feel that I don't need anything with respect to an API call, directly I can pass it, and the…
PAUL: Default 1.
PAUL: is just, I can say, the fast mode, which they refer.
PAUL: Text-only documents. If you have complex documents, really it doesn't work.
PAUL: So, always remember, when I'm working with the fast mode, it means that I will say that, okay, I'm not using any AI. Directly, I am using the modules which are available in Llama Parse.
PAUL: So, this is the free version. I will start with this one, and then…
PAUL: add LLMs. So, parse with LLM option is there. Now, LLMs, when I'm talking about, it will be focused much more, towards, like, table and images.
PAUL: Normal text, by default, it will come, but it cannot focus on graphs and charts.
PAUL: Okay, so simple tables and images, if you have, it works good. Because from the images using OCR, it can extract the data.
PAUL: But if you need more multimodal support, then you have to use some type of VLM. So, parse with LVM, which is very specifically written, so this is where your multimodal LLMs comes into the picture.
PAUL: And based on that, as you can see, GPT-40, GPT-40 Mini are pretty much long list of LLMs that they have, which can be used.
PAUL: Two parses at the same time? No, the idea is you need to focus on only parse with LLM or parse with VLLM.
PAUL: a lot of things which are deprecated, and even new models that have not been added in the documentation, but you can think it works really good. And GPT-4U, I can say this is really good, though it's a very costly API that you have.
PAUL: Yes, Sanket, if anybody wants to use any type of external services, yes, you, you don't, like, you can use your custom LLMs or custom VLLMs.
PAUL: But I can say that there are a few things, because, see, it's a paid service, so by default, they will invoke the model. You don't have to do anything.
PAUL: Okay, always remember this one. It means that they will be taken care of. You don't need to pass your API keys.
PAUL: Preset is just a configuration, nothing new.
PAUL: Now, okay. Now, this is the actual class that I'll be using. Similarly, parse with agent.
PAUL: Okay, so agent parsers are also available. So, complex document with images and tables. Now, this is the premium mode, which is the most costly mode, I can say, in Llama Parse.
PAUL: Whenever you are working with premium mode, I can say your response will… time will be high, as compared to fast mode. In fast mode, you can get the results within, I can say, less than 10 seconds, but in premium mode, it might take 30 seconds.
PAUL: Okay, so the latency will be higher.
PAUL: I feel that majorly in production, this premium mode is used a lot.
PAUL: With, layout agent is there for
PAUL: Understanding the layout of a document.
PAUL: If your document has a really complex layout, or if you're using different type of diverse document.
PAUL: At that particular moment, I feel that layout agent is really good in that.
PAUL: So, you can see it supports latex.
PAUL: for equation and moment syntax for diagrams. I think everybody knows about latex and moment.
PAUL: Mermaid. Using Mermaid, you can create workflows, LaTeX, to define your equations.
PAUL: Then, okay, so again, parse document with LLM.
PAUL: Pass documentation. Now, same.
PAUL: Here, you'll be just passing the document.
PAUL: Now, there are some trigger-based options also, which I'll be talking here in the auto mode.
PAUL: Okay, now, if you feel that, why these triggers are very, very important?
PAUL: I feel that this particular option is not really there in the other two frameworks that we have discussed.
PAUL: Triggers, it means that, okay, so let's start with something in the fast mode. It means that without AI or anything.
PAUL: But during the parsing operation, okay, it might have felt that, okay, there are actually charts, there are actually images. Okay, so you can actually switch that mode automatically, based on the trigger. It means that during the parsing operation, if it finds that, okay, there was a table, there was a image, there was a chart.
PAUL: Okay? So you can switch it from your, I can say, the free mode to the premium mode.
PAUL: This, particular option, I feel, is very, very important. In production, everybody's using, because it makes your life much more easier. During the parsing.
PAUL: mechanism, it can be, you can see, trigger on top of tables. If tables are there, automatically, the premium mode will be triggered. Similarly, trigger on images, trigger on regular expressions.
PAUL: Okay, where you can pass your own triggers, basically. Trigger on text, generally we don't use trigger on text, but again, I feel it's much better to use premium mode for images and tables.
PAUL: This is… one complete new feature that I feel, which is not available in any other frameworks.
PAUL: Now, the output mode, okay, so, like, text, markdown, JFON, XLS, PDF, okay, different type of output formats which are supported. You can have a look into the table from the documentation.
PAUL: Open check to pay, yes, that's the idea.
PAUL: When we say premium, it means that it will use more credits, because it will use, better, I can say, VLMs to do the extraction.
PAUL: Okay, so whenever you are working, you have to remember you are working with credits. So, when the premium mode is enabled, by default, if I'm talking so, like, 3 credits get exhausted at any point of time.
PAUL: So, that part… premium options. For premium, why the latency is high?
PAUL: I hope everybody knows that particular answer. For premium, why the retail says high.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Because you will be using LLMs and VLMs.
PAUL: They take more processing time.
PAUL: as compared to working with a smaller SLM, if I try to compare it with… Alright, so…
PAUL: Just remember, like, today I am discussing llama parts. After 6 months, most of the things will be deprecated.
PAUL: The updates are very good, the updates are very quick.
PAUL: Majorly, the issues that has been raised by developers, it get resolved within 72 hours, so I feel this is a very active one, but again, like, enterprise to enterprise, when you actually talk, then only it happens.
PAUL: Now, with respect to features, okay, so these things, now, whatever these modes preset, we'll be talking in our notebook directly, because I want you guys to focus directly here. Now, a few other options, like parsing options.
PAUL: Okay? So, language support is there, you can disable the OCR,
PAUL: Okay? Then comes diagonal text, unrolled columns, target pages, field separator.
PAUL: Now, really, like, these options might change in future. A lot of things that are deprecated, you can see here, parsing instructions. Previously, it was there. Similarly, structured output. Again, this is in beta state. Right now, not in alpha. So, always have a look into the documentation.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why, going forward, just focus on the documentation. I feel that the documentation is a faster way to do any type of implementation, as compared to just going through the entire notebook.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: I've told you, majorly, Yeah, okay. The features?
PAUL: Now, let's try to understand exactly what happens. Okay, now I will start with the notebook, so everyone can switch to the notebook.
PAUL: Yes, generally, stability is an issue, but, Muthasar, you have to understand that in the Enterprise Edition, there are few things, few modules are there which actually don't change.
PAUL: new premium features that are coming, that is right now in the beta state.
PAUL: Okay, and if you have any type of issues, if somebody is working enterprise to enterprise, you can actually let them know, and they actually solve majorly the issues with their engineering team.
PAUL: So, there are certain cases I know, okay, where clients have directly interacted and, based on that, a custom parser that might also be brought into picture. But only for enterprises, not for individual level.
PAUL: Hmm, correct.
PAUL: Alright, import issues, Raul, I think by this time we should have fixed it. Now…
PAUL: let's start with the LamaPass architecture. So, exactly what happens. There is a document class. So, always remember, like in Langshan, you have a document class, similarly here. So, you pass anything, it can be PDF extension.
PAUL: It can be TXT extension, it can be XLS, DockX, PPTX, okay, different extensions. So finally, when you load it using LlamaPass, so by default, it will become the Llama index document.
PAUL: You have to understand, behind the scenes, it will be using Lama Index always, though we have not learned about Lama Index, but I think everybody can assume, like, in Langshan, there was a document class. Similarly, here also, you have that particular document class.
PAUL: Now, here, everything is treated as a job. It means that you give any task to LlamaPass.
PAUL: It will be tricked as a job when I'm talking about it can be sync, like, asynchronous, as well as synchronous also. Now, you have to define. I think everybody knows the benefits of using async and sync, so for your simple task, always use synchronous, but in production, you have to actually move towards asynchronous-based solutions.
PAUL: Now, whenever I'll be executing any task, you will see that job and job result will come into the picture.
PAUL: Okay, so contains a parsed document. Okay, it means that once you have executed, for example, result is equal to llama parse, so what about the content that you'll be getting, the parsed content? Okay, so that is referred to as the job result.
PAUL: Okay, so only 3 things are there. First of all, initializing the LamaPars client, then once you will be passing any job, the task, in what type of task, whether it's a synchronous task or an asynchronous task.
PAUL: Then once the task is done, you'll be getting the entire past result within your job result. And finally, the Lama Index document object, which will be used with respect to text, metadata, it can be images, it can be other type of, I can say, layout structures within a document.
PAUL: So, first of all, this is the first time we are executing, and right now, as you can see here, parser that I have defined, and this is the LamaPars client that I'll be calling, the actual Llama Parse class that I have, and result type is equal to month now. So, going forward.
PAUL: Now, these parameters will increase, because right now I have kept it pretty much simple, only marked down.
PAUL: Sometimes, you might get an error, so you can always change the result type from Markdown to text, text to markdown, okay? And always look into the documentation, for different type of output format that you have. Okay, so these are the major supported ones.
PAUL: First of all, let me just take this one.
PAUL: And right now, these are some of the config categories that I have. So, here, if you just execute this cell.
PAUL: So, the idea was to look for different type of authentications, like API key, base URL which is available, output control, what is the result type, language, split by page.
PAUL: Now, I'm not using all the options. The idea was to show you the different options. Generally, it's a good practice to look into the documentation, but for now, I'm just showing you, because going forward, I'll be changing these parameters, the config parameters.
PAUL: Mode selection, you can see fast mode. Fast mode is the quickest mode, without AI mode. Then you have the default Premier Mode.
PAUL: Then you have auto mode. In auto mode, if you enable a fast mode, okay, and by default, there will be a trigger which will be enabled. Okay, you can pass your trigger. So generally, I prefer using auto mode much more, though…
PAUL: In production, it's much safer as compared to blindly using premium mode always.
PAUL: Then, different type of presets, already I have showed you in the documentation. Then, with respect to OCRs and images, like, you can disable OCR, high resolution OCR, extract charts, take screenshots, so all these type of options which are available.
PAUL: Then comes, layout, extract layout. Okay, do not unroll columns, so I feel that this extract layout is very important if you are working with respect to complex layout, documents.
PAUL: Structured output, now this is a new beta feature. So, right here, the default one is tech, the other one is based on JSON schema. Then you have prompts. Again, now this prompts module will entirely be removed in the future one. This is completely deprecated.
PAUL: Then comes performance, the number of workers, job timeout in seconds, and Vergos. So, most of the times, I prefer using Virgo's, but based on that, so number of workers, how much cores you have in your CPU, based on that, you can define it.
PAUL: So, let's start now executing. Okay, so two things that I'll be doing. So, first of all, let me pass some type of document.
PAUL: Boom.
PAUL: Now, this is a job result structure. So, what is a job result structure? It means that once you have done your parsing mechanism, then this is how
PAUL: actually, like, within the pages, all of your information will be stored. This is very, very important, because majorly you have to work with different type of indexing operations on top of this pages variable. Okay, like, rather than a variable, I will call it as a keyword now.
PAUL: Do you have any guidelines to choose the number of workers? Depends upon, like, how many cores I have on my CP, as simple as that.
PAUL: Page is equal to the, is equal to the number of documents.
PAUL: Okay, within a single one, within a single document, you have how many pages that you can simply think about?
PAUL: Alright, now I will start executing. A few other features are also there, but these I have already…
PAUL: talk, like, get markdown documents, get text documents, get image documents. You can extract images from the document, get Lama Index documents with text content, markdown, JSON, okay, directly this, on top of the, document, I can say, you can apply dot pages.
PAUL: By default, page-by-page data that you can extract.
PAUL: So, these are a few common features with respect to the job result that we are going to discuss.
PAUL: And then again, what are the, main… because majorly for developers, if you are working in production, majorly you have to work with async. Okay, for learning, you can use sync, no issues, but in production, that's work. And if you look into, majorly only A got added at every point of time. A load, A parse, A get images.
PAUL: Now, let's start with the passing part. Okay, so right now, as already, I have the attention. Attention is all you need research paper that I will be passing in most of the use cases.
PAUL: Okay, so here, this is our main initialization, so result type is equal to markdown. So, like, text, it can be text, it can be markdown.
PAUL: So, right now, inside the sample directory, I'm looking for whether this particular document is available, attention underscore paper dot PDF, okay? And then, this is the main line, as you can see, the document. So, within this document, you'll be getting the job result.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just pass it.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, as you can see, once I start my, parsing, okay, after the initialization of the Llama parse, so this is basically the job ID which has been defined for that particular task. So, parsing complete, the number of documents returned is 15,
PAUL: Okay, the document type, okay, it's 2767, characters, and always focus, because going forward, if I change
PAUL: the parsing mechanism, you will see the number of characters will be a little bit up and down. Somewhere it might be close to 3,000, if I go with premium modes. Okay, so the number of characters really changes.
PAUL: And now, initially, so this is exactly the content of the
PAUL: I can say. The research paper that we were looking into.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, I have just printed. So, directly, if I want to look into… so, just focus on this variable. This variable is important, that I feel. Okay, always try to debug what are the informations that you have here.
PAUL: Yeah. So… Can you see?
PAUL: The major information, okay, so for every type of pages within that document, I have a very specific ID. Okay, and these are all unique IDs, the IDs are not same. Embedding none, because I'm not doing any type of stuff. Metadata, pretty much blank. Okay, exclude, embedded metadata key. Again, this is pretty much blank.
PAUL: Then, you have relationships, pretty much blank. Metadata template, which is based on key and value. Again, this is blank. Metadata separators, again, slash name. Okay, so everything with respect to new lines. But your actual information is here. If you look into this text.
PAUL: Text is the actual, I can say, key.
PAUL: Through which you can access.
PAUL: Because everything is available under this text, so you can actually use a for loop, and you can look into each part.
PAUL: Okay, so for each of the pages that you have within your document. So, pretty much text. So that's why please focus on this particular variable. If you get any errors with respect to, like, list index, okay, any type of list issue, majorly, I feel that, yes, index sync issues that you might get, but always look into.
PAUL: This particular variable, exactly what has been extracted.
PAUL: This is very, very important.
PAUL: Blindly don't just try to execute the sales. Always look into exactly what is there.
PAUL: Okay, now…
PAUL: Raul is telling, remove this line from my import, new Llama Parse. No, Rahul. The new one is cloud services. Okay, Llama Parse has been included within your Llama Cloud Services, so both the imports should work fine. There should not be any type of issues.
PAUL: We have to verify manually, see, the idea is that you can always save this information somewhere, so that later you can actually look into, if you have some type of issue. So that's why I'm telling, like, this variable in LlamaPass is the most important, because generally, I spend time here looking into
PAUL: the information.
PAUL: So, in others, in, structured also, you can do the same stuff. In Doppling also, you can do the same stuff.
PAUL: After passing, please have it look into. So, that is the only request.
PAUL: Now, let's move into, because I have already executed, and I think that for everyone, it should be working fine.
PAUL: Now, let's try to look into some type of text output. If you try to compare, it's basically the same operation. Sometimes I might use markdown, sometimes I might use text. Okay?
PAUL: So here, only one thing that I have changed, which is basically the text part.
PAUL: Okay, that is the only thing.
PAUL: Let me now execute it.
PAUL: people who are getting API errors, please look into your ENV file and just be sure.
PAUL: In your code, you are calling all those ENVs, so please do a verification.
PAUL: Alright, similarly, as you can see here, now this is the text format.
PAUL: Attention is all you need. And right now, if you look into, can you see that in the text output?
PAUL: Like, if you look into the actual
PAUL: a paper. So, based on that, somehow it is trying to maintain the structure of
PAUL: If you really look into, like, there are species. It's not like that in one shot, everything is thrown to you.
PAUL: Okay. So this part, I feel that… This is really good. Okay, so if you just try to open the paper, so I think CTRL-F, need that…
PAUL: Okay, now, this part you can see. It's not like that everywhere. So, I feel that, yes, this is good.
PAUL: Okay, because in other passes I have seen with respect to text.
PAUL: Okay, so sometimes, with respect to indentation, that they might not use it directly. So I feel that this part is good, as compared to other parts.
PAUL: Okay. Now, whenever you are doing your parse operation, for sure it will, provide you the job result. So, similarly, like, markdown. So, this is the main initialization. So, this is the actual line of code that you need to focus, and this one.
PAUL: only two lines. Others are pretty much Pythonic stuff, simple to check whether the file is there or not.
PAUL: Okay, so right now…
PAUL: If you look into, I am passing llama pass, result type is equal to markdown, vergose is equal to true, and the idea is to show you that job result whenever. So, because of that, I have created this one. Okay, node takes a list of files, so for now, initially, I have a single file. If job result.
PAUL: Okay, I'm taking the first element from here, where I'll type the number of pages I'm finally looking into. Okay, so here the parsing will be enabled.
PAUL: People who are getting import error, please have a look into the package. In the last class, I've already talked about the installation. So really, in this class, I don't want to spend time on that one.
PAUL: Otherwise, after the class, please let me know. Import errors, just be sure you are using the correct version of Lama Index and Llama Pass.
PAUL: Okay, so based on the job result that I have, okay, so initially, for the first one, okay, so zero fintech, so basically the first page that I am looking into. So, I have taken result.pages very specifically, so that's why the first page is coming, and then I am looking into the top 500 characters.
PAUL: So, again, now the idea is to access individual pages.
PAUL: Okay? Now, just tell me how to access individual pages.
PAUL: I've already shown you that document variable. So, from there, just remember, you can always do that. I think…
PAUL: Pretty much using a for loop, you guys can do it.
PAUL: If you have this particular variable, yes, on top, you can apply enum.
PAUL: Oh, great.
PAUL: Now, text output, parser controls… Alright, now accessing individual pages.
PAUL: Alright, so here, okay, so a simple forward, okay, on top of that particular variable, like the document one. Okay, so through there, you can extract all the information that you have.
PAUL: Okay, so similar, just a for loop, and within the pages, and then I'm looking for the different type of contents which are available. The text, so you can see page.text, markdown, page.pd.
PAUL: Okay, then if you want to extract, images, so page.images, page.charts. Okay, it means that within your main variable, resort, okay, so you will always have those options. So, using a simple for loop, please do the extraction.
PAUL: And right now, it's telling that, okay, page 1, images 0, charge 0, okay? And then, preview with respect to the text that you have.
PAUL: Then for page 2, again, image 0, charge 0. So in this way, you can always get a detailed
PAUL: observation. Okay, so whenever you are doing a parsing page by page.
PAUL: And, really, like, images and charts, initially, we don't have. In the later stage in the paper, that we'll be getting it.
PAUL: Now, split by page option, again, another feature, using split by page to get separate documents per page. Now, this option, sometimes it might be useful, but again.
PAUL: Yes, by default, no, nothing is in auto mode. When I write auto, then only it will be. Right now, I'm just doing parsing.
PAUL: I'm not enabling, any specific feature, okay, like, defined premium, or to those type of presets that I'm not using.
PAUL: Now, the first one is, like, split by option, as you can see here. This option only needs to be enabled.
PAUL: Rest of the code is exactly the same.
PAUL: Okay, only one option, because previously you can see that I have been using only this one. The result type, sometimes I might be using markdown, sometimes I might be using text. But this option, like, each page becomes a separate document.
PAUL: Now, rest of the things, it's exactly the same, there is no change. Now, any use case where you might feel this option is important.
PAUL: Yes? Anyone?
PAUL: When you feel this option is important.
PAUL: Before, how it was splitting.
PAUL: Before, inside the document, all the pages were there, but right now, every page is converted into a document.
PAUL: Section-wise data. Section-wise, it's not necessary, Aniroth. Within a single page, you can have multiple sections.
PAUL: generally, like, I have seen, in few use cases where, like, for a book, okay, you create a very specific collection, and then page-wise, okay, you will be keeping chunks.
PAUL: Okay, like, for one page, again, three chunks, so you will be maintaining that page within your metadata.
PAUL: So, that's why in some cases it might be helpful, but again, it totally depends upon the case, because I don't feel that this option is always so much important as compared to others.
PAUL: Okay, so Document 1, Document 2, so you can see right now, each pages has been converted into different documents, and based on that, the content that we are staging.
PAUL: Now, coming to a few piece, separators and formatting, where you can pass your own
PAUL: Separators, okay, within the pages. So here, you can see result type markdown, split by false. It means that a single document will be there. Then, defining some page separators. So here, this is a custom separator that I have added.
PAUL: Now, this is,
PAUL: Like, whenever the page will change, okay? So that's why this particular separator will come into the picture, the page plate.
PAUL: Then, if you want very specific topics to be used, so page start. So, how many of you know about, tokens whenever you are working with CLS token, okay, then EOS, end of a sentence.
PAUL: like, tokens, whenever we are working with LLMs. Because at the end of the day, when we are converting your actual text into tokens, so to pass it to the LLM, you need to add those custom tokens
PAUL: for those LLMs, which has been defined. In Mistral, it's different. In Llama, it's different. So, those tokens can be different.
PAUL: But at least few said. So here, actually.
PAUL: You can add a very specific, like, I feel these are much more tokens, generally, when you are working with LLM training, then these things actually matter a lot. In case of RAD, not so much important, but with respect to LLM complete fine-tuning, it's very important.
PAUL: Okay, then, okay, verbose is equal to false, yeah, you can always use it through IP.
PAUL: Okay, now, again, on top of the same paper I amatic. So, if you really look into, it's pretty much the same thing, but few other
PAUL: parameters or arguments that I have passed here.
PAUL: Now let me execute it.
PAUL: the most atomic component, those are entities. Don't directly think in terms of entities.
PAUL: Rather than… with respect to tokens, it will be much easier.
PAUL: Because… Hmm.
PAUL: For LLMs, everyone has unique work that they do.
PAUL: while fine-tuning is pretty much like LLM retraining, when I'm talking, I'm referring to fine-tuning tasks. In those type of tasks, it's very important.
PAUL: Okay, now, based on the separators, very specifically that I have…
PAUL: Added, okay, so… split by face is equal to false.
PAUL: And if you look into work performed while at Google Brain, okay, worked, while at Google Research, 31st… okay, now, this particular, the number of characters, simply you can increase also, no issues.
PAUL: But for now, can you see, like, these type of information that is coming?
PAUL: Now, tell me, like, if you are doing any type of operation in the RAM, okay?
PAUL: And if you try to build your own chunking mechanism.
PAUL: In those cases, also, it can play a crucial role.
PAUL: Okay, because using these tags, okay, or later on through records, because these tags are pretty much fixed, so you can always maintain some type of metadata within your, during your chunking.
PAUL: So, probably, I can say that, okay, once this page ends, comes, and page breaks, so after this only you can start taking a new chunk.
PAUL: So you can always define some type of logics. It means that it gives you much more power.
PAUL: Do I feel that, yes.
PAUL: This option is really, really good when you are actually working on building your own custom chunkers, LLM fine-tuning in other places where you feel that tokens are important.
PAUL: So, really, it's good.
PAUL: It will be just one document with long text object, correct, Mohammad? If you want different documents, split by page, make this particular argument true, as simple as that, if you don't want a single document.
PAUL: Now, focusing on the… preset spark. Okay.
PAUL: So, by default, fast will be your major leaf friend, I can say, without AI. Quick extraction, no OCR, and fastest processing. Then you have a balanced mode, general documents, balance of speed and accuracy.
PAUL: Then you have that premium option, okay, where complex document. Complex… what is the meaning of complex? Always remember complex refer to
PAUL: The layout within that document is really complex. It has different types, like graphs, charts, tables, okay, append dates, references.
PAUL: probably a lot of other things that come into the picture. Okay, not only images and tables. That's why I want you guys to focus. It can be graphs, charts, a lot of other things.
PAUL: All right. Now, this… then you have structured, so very specifically, forms and tables optimized for structured data. Auto mixed content, because whenever you are, auto… so here you can actually use triggers.
PAUL: And particularly those triggers. It means that it will start with the fast preset, and then you can actually switch to premium preset if you find any type of images, tables, charts, okay, so that particular switching option that you have.
PAUL: Then, You have…
PAUL: I think I have missed something, like the scientific papers, this particular option I also told you. Then you have invoices. I think I have missed the forms part.
PAUL: Okay, so here, slides, that is also available. So, two things that are missing from here, always refer to the documentation, it gets updated. So, forms is also there, which is really good.
PAUL: Now, let's start with the fast preset. Okay, now, exactly, see, the idea is to look into the preset, okay, and later on, comparing different types of speeds that they do have.
PAUL: All these options applies to all the document types, or is it some options applicable to specific type? Nia Agarwal, it's totally up to you. When you are passing the number of documents, you need to check that.
PAUL: This is nothing related to Llama Parse, okay? Because how many files you are passing, that's totally up to you.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all, the fast mode I am using, result type text, verbose is equal to true. Okay, so just be sure you have those options. Then, the same PDF that I am passing.
PAUL: Okay, and based on that, let me see whether it's getting executed or not.
PAUL: Lama Buzz, does not give metadata details like Astra. Yes, directly, but…
PAUL: Manual injection that needs to be taken care of.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, if you look into the parsing time, 11.49 second.
PAUL: Then comes the content length, which is 3364. Like, if you really try to compare it with our initial, sometime I think I have done some characters.
PAUL: Okay, so… somewhere, I think. Alright, can you see the content length here?
PAUL: Okay, 2767. Now, actually, I've switched to the fast mode right now.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Where I went, yes.
PAUL: So, in the fast preset.
PAUL: I'm getting more number of characters, so I feel that here somehow. Okay, now, digital PDFs with selectable text, so for those type of documents, it really works good, because your core, I can say, like, frameworks.
PAUL: like, Pew Media and other PDF-based free modules that you have.
PAUL: Under the line that might be used, because this is entirely proprietary tech, so I don't know what type of framework that they used, but that is the idea.
PAUL: Now, this time, focus on this parsing time, because this will change. Okay, and probably the number of characters will change, because now I will move to the premium preset, where more credits are being used.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So…
PAUL: List index out of range, just be sure you are using result type physical text if you get an error. Okay, please do have a check. Sometimes you might get an error.
PAUL: People who are getting list index.
PAUL: Okay, please do check what is within this particular variable whenever you are loading, after loading exactly. So always check this document variable. If you have nothing, okay, it might create an issue, so please do have a check.
PAUL: Now, let's try to move ahead with the premium preset. Entire code is same, only one thing that I'll be changing is premium, okay? Now, two things that I need to focus on, the parsing and the number of characters.
PAUL: Alright, so if you have looked into the parsing time for this one, so parsing time is now close to 11.67 seconds.
PAUL: And last time, 11.49. So somehow, towards the higher side, the number of characters here, very specifically, so 3364 that I have.
PAUL: And in the premium mode that I'm getting is…
PAUL: Right now, it has reduced.
PAUL: Tobugini.
PAUL: when you look into, yes, 2, the parsing time is very, like, in milliseconds, I will say, but again, the core information that you have.
PAUL: Now, see, the document that I am passing, it's a fixed one, the research paper. Now, going forward, it is your job doing this complex type of PDF documents and test it out, really, how things are working.
PAUL: Okay, now, if I try to take some complex document, okay, so even I don't remember where I do have… just wait, I will try to take some complex docs, and let's see.
PAUL: Do you guys have some type of complex document?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: So you can actually pass it, okay, because for now, it's only the research paper that I am playing with, but try to use Canva for each document. Okay, not PDFs. Okay, like, within the PDF, probably a converted copy, but not pure PDF which has been built on Adopt Reader.
PAUL: Okay, for handwritten notes, please just be sure you are using high resolution OCR is equal to true, that particular parameter MS.
PAUL: Okay, now a few other presets. Okay, so this is the premium preset. Then you have the scientific preset, so handle, latex, equations, citations, okay. This should work good, because really, only one parameter that has changed here. Okay.
PAUL: And now, based on this, again, it will perform. So here, you can actually work with research papers, equations, and just be sure, that when you are working with the PDF creation, it should have some type of latex-based support.
PAUL: If there is no latest VIX support, there can be issues with respect to rendering sometimes.
PAUL: So, generally, Aniroth, using both, you can do parsing if you are working with parser.loadData, and similarly, parser.parse.
PAUL: But, whenever we are working with, presets, okay, so generally, we do use this one, okay, load data much more. If you are performing a direct parsing operation, it's majorly the paths from llamaparse.coms.
PAUL: So, with respect to presets, it's more about passing load data.
PAUL: Okay, now, for this scientific document, really, like, if you look into the parsing time and the number of characters.
PAUL: So, if you try to compare it with the premium one, okay, with the premium one, I feel that the number of characters were lesser. I know that, yes, this is a research paper somehow, so it's the layout, because for every preset, behind the scenes.
PAUL: the Llama guys have predefined layouts. Okay, because of those layouts, it works really good.
PAUL: So, you can see the premium reset really failed, because based on the document type that I passed, which is much more scientific. So, here you can see, yes, the parsing time has increased now as compared to premium mode. Okay, and again, the content length has increased.
PAUL: So, 3234. Last time, it was close to 300, it was missing close to 200 characters that I can see.
PAUL: As far as it works.
PAUL: Okay, try that, because a lot of parameters are there that you guys can play and inject, as simple as that. One is asking, sir, I'm trying to run… showing,
PAUL: rolled out timer is not running in the notebooks, really. I have no idea. Okay, Mama, yes, you can test it out. Dig Vijay, let's say we have PDF having formulas, and it contains some invoices in the PDF.
PAUL: Okay, so generally in that case, if you have different type of file formats, I'll be using that… plate.
PAUL: Okay, and the idea is that once you split the PDF, then only… okay, so it means that you should have some type of layout detector. Okay, for every page, you'll be looking into what type of layout that you can get, and based on that, you can apply a preset.
PAUL: Yeah, so two level of conditional logic that needs to be applied there, Vijay.
PAUL: Alright, now let's move to some others. Invoices. Really, I don't have invoices with me, so you guys can simply test it out. Only one thing that needs to be changed is the preset. Okay, so invoices, it can be received. Okay, so transactional documents in simple terms.
PAUL: Now, the slide preset is there. I feel that in future, it will be removed.
PAUL: Okay, I'll move into some other module, but for now, you have this one.
PAUL: So, directly, you can pass your TPTX files
PAUL: Now, let's try to compare a few presets that we do have.
PAUL: So, the fast, the balanced, and the premium, three things. Okay, and then the idea is to simply, using a for loop, I'll be activating all those three, and let's try to compare exactly what is the difference with respect to the speeds that they have, the total number of characters that they are extracting. So, let's focus on those counts.
PAUL: So, I think if I leave a boilerplate in some cases, you can… you guys can pass it. For example, if I've defined the main function. Later on, I think you guys can pass it.
PAUL: You have to just add one line of code. Please let me know.
PAUL: Can you guys do it by yourself?
PAUL: Because this is the actual line that you need to pass.
PAUL: Similarly, Nick.
PAUL: So here, probably, this part, okay. Now, whatever is that variable name, okay, so just be sure, based on that, you are passing it.
PAUL: Okay, so you don't have to use a lot of FN4, similarly for slide preset also that you can do.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: Now, let's… I have executed the comparing the presets, so let's try to look into… Okay, now this is somewhere based on the API execution. In the fast mode, it's taking close to 8.11 seconds.
PAUL: Balanced mode, okay.
PAUL: 7.32 seconds, and the number of characters are 3364. In the premium one, if you looked this time, it's coming close to 3381.
PAUL: So, really, if you try to understand… okay. Now, see, now these times are totally dependent upon your document.
PAUL: Okay, if your document is bigger, it will take more time. If it has more number of pages, it will take more time. If you have lesser pages, less time.
PAUL: As simple as that.
PAUL: Yes, it might change. It's not every time it's fixed, okay? So you can see, like, this time, very specifically, 11.21 with 3321. Last time, I invoked that one.
PAUL: So, oof… Probably a different layout that might… have been activated.
PAUL: Okay, so preset premium markdown, okay? And here you can see the characters have actually changed.
PAUL: Always look into these things, because this might change, it's not necessary.
PAUL: Okay, and this time with respect to the preset definition that I have passed here.
PAUL: Okay, so I think some change will be there with respect to… Okay, now last time, the result type was markdown. Okay, that's why the number of characters are different. This time, the result type is text. So that's why the number of characters are different.
PAUL: Okay, so whoever might think that, okay, so the output type, I am changing, so because of that, the number of characters might get affected.
PAUL: what is the significance of character length with respect to preset? We can always check that, which one is providing. At any point of time.
PAUL: And always use the same output type. Okay, so whenever you are doing your testing, don't try to mix both.
PAUL: Okay, so there is no direct relationship. I feel that premium works better most of the time as compared to other presets.
PAUL: The real estate underscore fast is not loading the document.
PAUL: How many of you are getting? Because preset underscore fast, really, I have not used anywhere. I'm using presets, so here, it should be only fast. Just be sure you are passing the correct keywords.
PAUL: Site 3 should always look into that document variable if you are working with Margotown, so some things might not be there. So, always please check that.
PAUL: Okay, alright, now let's move to some passing modes also.
PAUL: So, with respect to different type of modes, so fast mode, premium mode, auto mode, okay. So, fast mode, skip the OCR, fastest processing, then in premium mode, already discussed, auto mode, so this part that we'll be talking about in detail.
PAUL: Okay, so… the first one… there isn't much difference. Here's the difference…
PAUL: But sometimes there can be. So, it generally depends upon the type of document, Raul. So, like, in your case, 2767, it's pretty much the same one.
PAUL: So it's good, but the parsing time, if I look into premium, was fastest compared to fast.
PAUL: Okay, greedy.
PAUL: Alright, now let's get back and let's explore, according to the documentation, the past modes that you have. Okay, so this one, I feel that this is…
PAUL: much more important if you're working Llama parts in production, because this is where the actual things will change, because auto mode is the most…
PAUL: prefer the mode that I use.
PAUL: Okay, in production, because directly using premium mode for every type of document, it's not a good practice. Okay, because a lot of credits will be exhausted. So I feel that auto mode is somewhere that you should select.
PAUL: And now, the different type of parse, okay, with LLMs, without LLMs, so Agent Take, AgentPlus, so few options that I have gifted here. So, let's start with the fast mode. Okay, so previously.
PAUL: So, fast mode is equal to true, so it will skip the OCR. Now, for… if you want to enable the OCR, what is the parameter?
PAUL: High, NFL, high res.
PAUL: If you remember that particular parameter which you have to use, Alright.
PAUL: I'm now here.
PAUL: Okay, the premium mode, again, with respect to text, okay, I think the executions…
PAUL: Pretty? Okay, now, 5.3 is the actual one where I want you guys to focus on, because 5.1 and 5.2, it's exactly the same piece of code that we have discussed about.
PAUL: Now, auto mode, as I was talking about, auto mode with triggers. So, this is actually what you will be using in your actual official work, I feel. Okay, so it means that enable automatic mode selection. Now, here you can always pass on triggers.
PAUL: If you have diverse type of documents, it's very, very important that, okay, for complex documents, please go with something premium. Otherwise, you can always use the fast option.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, in this way, you can do, or otherwise, if you have some type of a program which will detect the layout, and based on that layout detection, if you want to apply some type of logic.
PAUL: Okay, so the core fundamental logic that comes, it's based on layout.
PAUL: Okay, so always remember that. If you cannot understand the layout, it becomes a problem. So here, so the auto mode is equal to true, and then to…
PAUL: that I have kept it two main triggers, auto mode trigger on image, in-page, and on-table in-page.
PAUL: Okay, so here, upgrade pages with images and upgrade pages with tables. Now, this is the part where the premium mode will be switched on if this particular trigger condition is true in both of the cases.
PAUL: Any way to check on parsing configuration that gets applied based on the mode selected.
PAUL: Any way to check, always check your code. In the code, you will be writing the logic. You need to focus on the code only, no?
PAUL: Alright, now this is the…
PAUL: configuration, okay, and based on that, simply… okay, so the idea is if there is simple text, fast parsing will be enabled. If there are pages with images and tables, then premium parsing will be enabled. Now.
PAUL: This, like, going forward, if you are working with Llama parts in any project, please do use this option. This is the most…
PAUL: I feel that the best option that you have, tell now, like, everything that you have learned, tell now.
PAUL: Because this mode, I feel, is very, very packed.
PAUL: As compared to others.
PAUL: Preset is equal to fast, and fast underscore mode, it's the same stuff when you do. At the end of the day, we're doing a operation on top of fast mode.
PAUL: Who cares?
PAUL: Now, let's try to move into auto mode with text triggers, so very specifically with respect to
PAUL: Auto mode, trigger on text and page, so table, figure, and equations. Now, again, you can see a very specific pattern that we have kept it.
PAUL: And based on that pattern, it will try to initiate that, whether it's available or not.
PAUL: Now, text triggers, totally depends upon you, I don't use it a lot.
PAUL: based on majorly, I feel that I use auto-triggers on images and tables, which are much more important. Text-based triggers, if it matters to you, you can use. Then, similarly, you have regex-based triggers also.
PAUL: Okay, so where you can pass your own custom regulates.
PAUL: Okay, so now, as you can see, very specifically, like, example, I've just kept it percentages and dollar amounts.
PAUL: then auto mode with JSON configuration. Okay, so right now, in this particular JSON, I am defining a config. So if you want much more advanced config at any point of time, you can pass it here.
PAUL: See, I feel that this config is very, very important if you're working in production, so just be sure that you are passing these particular config settings. So, on image, true, onTable, true, on text patterns, figure, table, chart, everything that I am passing. Fallback mode.
PAUL: past upgrade mode premium.
PAUL: So, I feel that this gives you much more, like, making it much more flexible at any point of time.
PAUL: Please let me know, this JSON configuration, because I use it widely, so I feel that you guys also should use it.
PAUL: The conditional part, yes, I feel that this is much easier at any point of time to handle, because this particular auto-config that you have, you can directly pass it.
PAUL: Okay, so as you can see here, I'm directly passing the JSON file. So here you have more control.
PAUL: Okay, because you can always do it through code, but I feel this is…
PAUL: more powerful as compared to directly passing it one by one. But always remember, you can pass these logics, okay? And by default, the fallback mode is always, like, it will always start with fast, and then if there is a trigger, which is, like, which will be enabled, then by default, the premium will come.
PAUL: Now, similarly, you can… I feel here you have the flexibility of changing the upgrade mode to probably balanced mode if you want.
PAUL: Okay, now, that is not available directly in the code, but through JSON, you can pass it.
PAUL: Arian is asking why this is a standard. Working with JSON and YMS, it has been a common config standard in Python, that's why.
PAUL: Sankumar is asking difference between auto-trigger text and trigger image. If there will be an image within that particular page of the PDF, then that… if image is there, it will be upgraded to the premium mode.
PAUL: If there is some type of text where, very specifically, I'm telling figure, table, and charts, so now, based on this, again, it will be upgraded to
PAUL: Okay, now, see, these are basically keywords that I am passing, and at every point of time, when you are working with PDFs, below that image, you might have some type of figure, table, chart, which is written.
PAUL: Excellent.
PAUL: Okay, now let's focus on… some…
PAUL: Okay, now, granular modes. Okay, so let me just go back to the documentation.
PAUL: Alright, so somewhere here, I think, is…
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the one with respect to advanced pathing.
PAUL: So, here, different type.
PAUL: or parsing with LLM, with VLM, with agent, with AgentPlus. So here, there are more options. In the notebook, I have not kept every option, but please do explode from here.
PAUL: So, first of all, granular load. So, here I'm just printing out everything in one shot, so that you guys can quickly read it. So, parse page without LLM, parse page with LLM, okay, parse page with VLM, so we are very specifically a multimodal visual language model which is used.
PAUL: Parse page with agent.
PAUL: parse speech with layout agent, okay? Now, this parsing, I feel it's more important, because complete layouts and others
PAUL: You can actually extract the information. But, really, like, the…
PAUL: Now, really see, by default, do you want to use an LLM for parsing?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: How many of you feel that this option is… Good.
PAUL: Passing page with LLMs.
PAUL: Yes, for how many of you think that it's a good option?
PAUL: But you have to always understand the pros and cons. I don't feel that I should use LL.
PAUL: But really?
PAUL: Because for every type of document, if you want to pass it to the LLM, the final cost, only for that parsing.
PAUL: I can say the parsing component will be very, very high.
PAUL: So, really, working with LLMs is not my choice, really. Okay, now, if I want to perform some type of operation.
PAUL: Okay, because if I want to do a parsing, why LLL? Why not select a VL? Because I feel that this option is much better, and this option will be much more costly also.
PAUL: Because most of the multimodal token cost that you have, it's towards the higher side.
PAUL: So, like, these options, really, I don't prefer, but one option that I pay for is this one, parse page with layout agent. When you have really very complex layout, like, within a document, you might have 10 different type of layouts.
PAUL: But in those cases, it's really good.
PAUL: Because none of the parsers will work. This is a… This problem, I have even faced it, so I'm letting you know. Because this option is only the good one.
PAUL: Okay, other than that, other options, you can leave with this, but really, I'm not a fan, because I don't want my parsing to be very, very expensive.
PAUL: If you feel you can use it.
PAUL: And with respect to LLMs, if you are directly working, use this option better. Like, these two options, I feel, which is much more important.
PAUL: They are talking about path agent, like, with agent, so an agentic reasoning for complex pages.
PAUL: Okay, now, this is very, very costly. It uses close to, like, 3 to 4 credits in one shot. So, again, a very costly operation. I feel that the other
PAUL: mechanisms of using somewhere balanced and premium, they will be good, but directly passing these, again, not a good solution. Always remember that.
PAUL: It's just a function, Janika. What is the agent? The name of this particular function that they have passed it as an agent.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Because behind the scenes, they might be using a set of agents to do this task, but again, proprietary tech. We really don't know what we should pass it to.
PAUL: Now, comparing with parsing mode, though, now see, within the next step, till now.
PAUL: You have already explored some presets, some modes, okay. Again, the same stuff that can be passed for this type of operation.
PAUL: Okay, so comparing fast mode and premium mode.
PAUL: You have to remember, if you pass, like, preset with respect to fast and preset is equal to premium, is equal to balance, all those means the same stuff. It doesn't change. Like, fast underscore mode, and previously you were passing preset is equal to fast. So, at the end of the day, it's the same stuff that you were doing.
PAUL: Okay, so here… and, right now, do you know what is the exact number based on the, file format that LamaPar supports? Okay, the claim that they have based on that. It's really, like, close to 130 or 140, I think.
PAUL: Different type of file options that they do pass.
PAUL: Okay, supported document type. Okay, now, here is the official list that has been provided. Few betas are also there.
PAUL: So, if you really look into the supported document types, so PDM, but other documents, really, I have not heard about so many type of…
PAUL: options that they have provided. In images also, you can see. Really, spreadsheets. So, as compared to others, I feel this is much more powerful as compared to top links or unstructured. If you really look into the document types.
PAUL: Okay, few things are supported, but I can say few file types are very unique to Llama parse only.
PAUL: Alright, we'll be going for a break, don't worry. Okay, so always refer to the supported document types, it keeps on updating, and in some other places, the claim goes to, like, close to 140 different type of extensions.
PAUL: So, if you try to look into the results, I've done a comparison, fast mode, premium mode, auto mode, okay.
PAUL: This is exactly the results that you are getting.
PAUL: So, premium mode, yes, it's taking more time. Auto, again, like, within the auto mode, it's a good practice to pass your triggers
PAUL: Otherwise, it will be pretty much the fast one.
PAUL: Okay, because here, autofills are somewhere… Okay.
PAUL: It is faster as compared to that.
PAUL: Rishi, you can pass result type is equal to text, and you can test it out whether it's giving
PAUL: Always look into that document, it's variable, it's very, very important.
PAUL: Alright, what's the time? Okay, so 10.40. Let's go for a break, okay?
PAUL: And then we will start our discussion.
PAUL: Alright, San Kate, timer, I have started. Will you start the project discussion? Let's see if this notebook gets completed. We can do it.
PAUL: If there is a document having geo-coordinates information.
PAUL: Then, how we would treat it?
PAUL: intuitive coordinate information, fine, like, geospatial data for those. We do have different type of
PAUL: Databases that we do prefer much more than
PAUL: I don't think… but if you have the information, it's totally, like, how it is represented within tables or through JSON, based on that, I have to take the decision.
PAUL: Unless the last… so, really, like, people who have missed the classes, previously, it doesn't matter so much, because once we start the project.
PAUL: Just focus on last to last week.
PAUL: Okay, yeah, the parsers are not so much important. At any point of time, go to the documentation and refer, that's better, rather than looking into the lectures. It's just that different parsers, that was the idea.
PAUL: But just be sure, everyone, and that at least, like, today, if we start a little bit also with the project at tomorrow, and next week, everybody is available.
PAUL: Santeet, yes, if you are suggesting fee, generally there are all those, I can say, different type of compliance.
PAUL: Okay, so there is no problem using, but yes, if the data is very, very sensitive.
PAUL: I won't suggest using llama parts.
PAUL: The bed is very, very sensitive.
PAUL: But it's not a good practice.
PAUL: The idea is that all the information you showed her.
PAUL: But it's not very sensitive, and the client is fine.
PAUL: Because I know in production, many people are using Llamophore.
PAUL: Because it's easy, it means that really you don't need to do a lot of stuff.
PAUL: As compared to docklinks and unstructured, you need to build hybrid frameworks. Okay, like hybrid data ingestion. For one task, you might use one structure. For other type of file type, you might change the parcel. So, those type of things that you can always play with it.
PAUL: I'm in EU region, how do we add API client for that?
PAUL: there is a really region-wide, I don't think any problem is here. Directly, you can get the API.
PAUL: Aniroth, you can use a premium mode if you have formulas.
PAUL: Okay, and just be sure the formulas are…
PAUL: rendered using latex, then only it is helpful, otherwise not helpful.
PAUL: Mudhasar is asking, what is the best alternative for ulama? As we using here.
PAUL: Really, ulama is different, and Llama Index is totally different.
PAUL: Ulama… through Ulama, you can access embedding models and models. You can play with the…
PAUL: Llama Index a total different gene, I think.
PAUL: What are some of the considerations? It depends upon the file type, the layout.
PAUL: You have to do a detailed analysis, and based on that, you take the information.
PAUL: Document links… Yes.
PAUL: top links, I will say, for formulas, it depends upon, like, how the formulas have been rendered.
PAUL: If it is through Latinx, it's good.
PAUL: If it's directly, like, somebody has done the copy-paste of an image within that particular document, it becomes a problem then.
PAUL: Aniroth. Okay, so really, that… how the PDF was rendered, it matters to us.
PAUL: Of course, they are different, but which model can help?
PAUL: The higher number of parameters, better the model Mutatha. Always remember.
PAUL: Check the params. If you have higher params, for sure it will be better.
PAUL: Salaman, later on, I will switch on the mic, not now.
PAUL: Tej is asking, so Lama Index is recommended for parsing? No, you can use documents on structure, no restrictions in that.
PAUL: kill, upgrade mode, upgrade mode is just like the auto mode, okay? In Llama Bar, same stuff.
PAUL: Auto and upgrade.
PAUL: Viraj, in Llama Pass, can you play with both preset and pass more, or just, one time?
PAUL: You can play with both the combinations, Viraj.
PAUL: But I will suggest start one by one, and then try to combine both.
PAUL: Parryforma, generally in those type of cases, like, context comparison that needs to be done, okay, because if the LLM is fixed, you can't change the LLM. That's the only solution.
PAUL: context completion that I was talking about earlier. You can do that. If you can't change the LLM, if the LM is fixed, so you can work on the context compression part.
PAUL: In your use case.
PAUL: Llama Pass without LLM works here? Yes, Llama Pass is a paid service. So, yes, it will work.
PAUL: How can we store image extracted from Llama Index? How can we store in a folder saved the information?
PAUL: There is no issue. You can extract images.
PAUL: And, see, it's not Lama Index. People… many people are telling in chat, we are not doing Llama Index, it's Lama Parse.
PAUL: So don't get confused.
PAUL: Murthasa, like, parse with LLM, it will be text, unimodal.
PAUL: Okay, and very specifically, like, VLMs, if you switch to… okay, now that will be multimodal. So, for premium mode, yes, behind the scenes, it uses it. So, that's why it charges you much higher.
PAUL: In parallelms, you have the option to plead with other
PAUL: Elements also, where here you don't have the option of that.
PAUL: In the premium mode directory.
PAUL: Difference between Llama Index or Llama Chain, both are same framework, the same task can be achieved by LandChain as well as by Llama Index Source.
PAUL: There is no restriction in that.
PAUL: Alright, now let's get back, let's get stock 3.
PAUL: Now, does Llama Crowd provide embeddings API too?
PAUL: Embeddings API is not there.
PAUL: Because, there are few LAMA-based embedding models, But,
PAUL: Those are pretty much open source. Okay, so why will base through some circles? They don't have a premium embedding model.
PAUL: Okay, so majorly, most of the research, if I'm talking about Llama-based models, that is also totally open source, Lama-based embedding models, that is also open source. So with respect to LLMs and others, you can get it anywhere, from freely hosted.
PAUL: Now, Anita was asking, Llama Pass has its own champion.
PAUL: No.
PAUL: See, whenever I'm talking about parsers, you have to focus on the part that parsing is… once the parsing is done, then chunking comes.
PAUL: Okay, so any parsers, few of them might have the functionality of giving you the chunks, but you have to understand, like, going forward, you should always use your own chunker.
PAUL: Because the chunking application, it really changes. It can be based on file types, it can be based on layout, so you might have multiple conditional logics.
PAUL: Alright, now let's start with some type of,
PAUL: Okay, file formats which are supported, okay? So, the first one is just a PDF, I think.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the part with OCR options. I feel that if you want to really work with handwritten page documents, you can.
PAUL: pass here this option. Very, very important. High risk, OCR is equal to true.
PAUL: Okay, so better OCR quality that you will get by default if you are not passing and making it false.
PAUL: So, if you want to disable the OCR, okay, so disable OCR is equal to true.
PAUL: But by default, it's a… the default one is always, like, false, I can say.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, really, I'm showing you this option, so it's totally up to you which option you want to use, because really, you have to do a lot of experiments based on your data, and then finally come out with it. So, here, a sample HTML file that I'm passing, so I'm changing it from PDF to HTML this time.
PAUL: I don't know whether this will work or not.
PAUL: Let's see… Okay, so, alright, extracted content info I'm getting.
PAUL: So, majorly, like, now this particular feature, if I'm talking about, this feature is available everywhere. In LandChain, it is available. Okay, in LandChain data loaders, there also we talked about HTML and docklings were talked about in unstructured documents, you…
PAUL: We have talked about. But, you have to understand, these files should be static.
PAUL: Okay, so if you have dynamic JS, okay, so it becomes a problem. Static works really good in most of the HTML paste.
PAUL: Okay, so… Alright, so here, markdown already, I've showed you this particular example.
PAUL: Okay, I think because of document 0. So, if somebody gets the error, please always look into documents. Can you… able to access it or not?
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, now let's look into some other file formats. So, parsing, this one, okay, so this is, right now Microsoft documents. So here, all the cells I have provided, if you want to do any type of parsing mechanism.
PAUL: I think sample.
PAUL: doc, sample.xls, different type of file formulas that you have.
PAUL: So, simply, you can play with this different type of file formats, and based on that, you'll be getting the results. So right now, based on docx, okay, so this is the job ID. I'm not, printing out the results from here. I've just done the initialization, and you can actually look into the result variable.
PAUL: Right now, there is a single document with respect to the text, okay, page 1, archive, Google, figures…
PAUL: Alright, fame formation that I'm getting here.
PAUL: Now, let's… Try to pass something new.
PAUL: parsing Excel sheets, okay. So, Excel sheet support is also there, PPTX. So, every type of support, majorly you have, again, working with images. So, this one, I feel that you can really work with it. So, this is actually an OCR.
PAUL: Okay, which will be applied.
PAUL: Okay, now, really, we don't know what type of OCR they use. Okay, so that's… we are pretty much in blind. So, in other, I feel that whenever I'm working with OCR, it's good to know that which OCR is failing. But in this case, we really don't have any idea.
PAUL: Then, parsing multiple file types together. Okay, so using Glob, okay, or you can use something like this, and this way you can actually get it. Okay, for this type of task, LanChain directory loaders, so that is somewhere I feel that you can actually work with it, and play with this one.
PAUL: And now, for every type of file, whenever you are working, just be sure that you can make a setting, okay, only for PDF, I might be using an auto mode. Similarly, for HTML files, you really don't need
PAUL: And, mode, okay, where you want to switch to premium.
PAUL: Because HTML, by default, preserves majorly all the structures. Okay, Markdown. Again, for Markdown files, I don't feel that I need to work with premium.
PAUL: But probably in the markdown, if something there is latex, then I might switch it.
PAUL: So always, it depends upon the structure, and based on that, we take the decision, like, which one to work. But just be sure that in HTML files, you should not use any type of premium options, okay? Because by default, I have seen majorly all the workers
PAUL: All of the type of parsers really work with HTML. Good.
PAUL: Then, coming to some type of extraction of… this is a multi-modal parsing feature.
PAUL: Okay, in the documentation. So, you can extract charts, you can extract images, so all those type of options which are available. So here, you can see, so probably in page 9 of the attention is all you need PDF that we got.
PAUL: Page 10, page 13. Now, this operation takes time, because multimodal, whenever we are talking about what will be used behind the scenes, guys.
PAUL: a multimodal LLM, or VLLM that we do use.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, total 5 type of charge that has been extracted here. It's not really… we don't know whether it's SLM… it's not SLM for sure, it will be some type of VLM. And VLM always have higher number of parameters, okay, if you try to compare it with…
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, now comes with respect to screen, shots. Okay, capture these screenshot. Now, this particular option is also there.
PAUL: Okay, now if you feel that the visual rendering of any type of features that comes, really, I don't use this one, okay, because I don't feel this option, but in some use cases, it might be…
PAUL: important, but really, I have not played with this option. So, like, if you feel that, do you want to use screenshots from your document?
PAUL: Yes, then you can play with this multimodal feature, again.
PAUL: Then, coming to high-resolution OCR already, we have discussed about just one parameter that you need to switch into, and you can actually test this out with handwritten documents.
PAUL: Okay, now coming to vendor multimodals.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the part, okay, because till now, whatever the thing that we have discussed, it's very, very specific to Llama Pass. It means that without an API key, you can work. API key means Llama, cloud API key you need, but the OpenAI API key.
PAUL: Because I think in my ENV, it is already configured. Now, you can select which model you want to use.
PAUL: No.
PAUL: For some, it might be useful, and for somebody, it might not be. Now, GPT-4.0. Now, this is one of the best models which Okinea has provided yet.
PAUL: I can say. Really, really good. Anybody who's worked with GPT-40? This is very costly.
PAUL: Okay, the token cost is really high.
PAUL: MS could not hear you. I think the audio is fine, please do.
PAUL: Check.
PAUL: Okay, now, how many of you feel that you can pass your, like, optional proprietary LLMs here?
PAUL: Okay, and the list is already available in the documentation I showed you. You can play with different models.
PAUL: Now, here, I have simply passed your API key, so you can configure it in your ENV, and then you can actually pass it.
PAUL: Olama Ulama support, I don't think they have. People asking, because with respect to Ulama.
PAUL: I doubt Ulama is there.
PAUL: Because majorly, I feel they have proprietary texts here. As you can see, Azure is there.
PAUL: Okay, GPT 4.0, this is fine, this is deprecated, but you can use it till now. I don't think supported models, let me just check here…
PAUL: I don't… they don't have ULAMA. If you really look into the list, which is available here, of all the multimodal support.
PAUL: It's majorly all the GPT models, Anthropic-based models, Gemini-based models.
PAUL: Okay? So, really, it is not available here.
PAUL: Okay, so, yeah, see, the support with external LLMs.
PAUL: I feel that… because Llama has its own family of elements, which is widely used, even they don't have the support for that one.
PAUL: Okay, so these are all VLNMs.
PAUL: Okay, so all VLMs support. Okay, so multimodal support is there for all this…
PAUL: One, so ULAMA is not supported.
PAUL: Okay, many people ask the question about Olama, not available here.
PAUL: Okay, so multi-vendor models, so simply switch and play with the options which are available. You can bring your own API key and pass it.
PAUL: Now, complex visual understanding now.
PAUL: For complex visual understanding, GPTO 4.0 works really, really good, or Opus.
PAUL: Opus models. Opus models are also really, really good at any point of time that you can play with.
PAUL: Yes, DeepSeek OCR, Raul, yes, DeepSeek OCR is good, and you can integrate with, because I think there are some integrations with Llama Index which are directly available.
PAUL: text to Vick now.
PAUL: Now, a very specific function, okay, so if you want to extract now, at any point of time, if you feel that, okay, you want to extract images from a PDF document, okay, you can always do this.
PAUL: So, extract images example, image extraction from documents. So, some people might have asked it, so this particular function also that I have kept it, and based on that, you'll be getting.
PAUL: Now, if you want a paid screenshot, so those params are also available. Okay, you can make those parameters as true, and you can play with them, include object images. Okay, so object images refer to the chart, graphs, okay, by default, the images which are available.
PAUL: And if you have this particular screenshot available, so you will get the full information, but if you filter, I just need the image, I just need the chart, then include object images is much more important.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, image and chart metadata.
PAUL: So, let me just try to look into what are the image and chart metadata that it can extract from the documents.
PAUL: Multimodal is much more, I can say, a premium support.
PAUL: Okay, so Viraj, using multimotors will give you better results.
PAUL: Even I feel that if you directly use premium, only the default premium, because if you use premium, do you think that you know what you are actually doing behind the scenes?
PAUL: Really, I don't know that field.
PAUL: Okay? You can switch the model, doesn't matter. Jupyter 4 is deprecated, but it also works. Not a problem.
PAUL: You can always switch different models.
PAUL: I feel that using VLMs, it's a very costly operation, I agree, but you know that, okay, I am actually using this. Whereas, using just the premium mode, I really don't know behind the scenes.
PAUL: Okay, so you know that, okay, you are getting the past information, but
PAUL: Actually, what is taking place behind? You have no idea.
PAUL: So, VLMs are costly, but again, you can always use it. Now, this particular option of layout extraction.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, majorly, I feel that this is the most important step in data bars.
PAUL: layout. If you really don't know the layout, you cannot build a good path.
PAUL: So, there has to be some type of algorithm which helps you to detect this particular layout.
PAUL: Okay, and a few other frameworks are there, like layout passes and others, okay, which can help to decide.
PAUL: Okay, alright, and I will lay out extraction. Now, for this particular option, only this particular parameter that needs to be enabled in true condition.
PAUL: If you look into rest of the task, it's exactly the same. Okay, now let's focus on the layout, which…
PAUL: Might get detected here.
PAUL: Armani, fine, if I have missed your question, okay, you can ask me later on, always.
PAUL: So, one thing I can say is that, always, because, see, in our page 1, page 2, I think it was pretty much text, that's why the layout type is list. That is being detected. Okay, so, probably, if I increase this number to, let's go, till 10,
PAUL: Okay, let's see whether the layout changes or not.
PAUL: So, I feel that if somebody is building a good parsing framework for their own rack pipeline, you really need to work on layout.
PAUL: Because, most of the libraries have made your life easier. You really don't need to spend a lot of time, just pick up one, like Doppling, unstructured, get started. Okay, but that layout detection might be, like, totally different.
PAUL: Okay, because to understand the layout, like, LM layout, anybody has heard about those type of research papers through which you actually detect
PAUL: Okay, like, layout LM is very, very famous, actually, in doing that, but, a lot of new things also came. So, like, Detectron 2 based,
PAUL: layout parcel. That is good, I will say, but again, computationally very, very expensive task. Always to do.
PAUL: Now, if you want to maintain column structure, okay, if you have data in such a way, okay. Now, this particular option, anybody has read research papers where they have seen two columns?
PAUL: Because, majorly, the research paper that comes, you'll be getting that.
PAUL: How to, determine LAMA over OpenAI, or local parsing? You don't have to, you have to take the decision. If you have the budget to use Llama Parse, go with that. If you don't have, you need completely open source implementations, stick with Docklinks.
PAUL: You… the decision always comes, like, whoever is leading the project, based on that, because Lama Power actually comes with a price.
PAUL: And monthly billing will be close to, like… depends upon the number of documents, but I've seen the billing comes close to…
PAUL: $1,500 to $1,000, okay, based on the number of documents, like, close to…
PAUL: 37K documents that I've been working with. Okay, so it comes, and then again, the size of the document also matters. So there is no way to determine, you can always do your initial testing. If you feel that dockling is failing, unstructured is failing, and there can be a condition where Llama parts even might fail.
PAUL: You have to really understand.
PAUL: Okay? It is not necessary the parsers that I have taught you everything about. It means you have the data, bring it. It doesn't happen in real life.
PAUL: If you have some type of complex documents, even LAMA parse might fail.
PAUL: And it's a common thing.
PAUL: In those cases, you really need to take care of what you have to do, what you don't have.
PAUL: Say, documents are sensitive, so I don't send to LlamaPass. Yes, that will be a good practice, because, see, really, like, if I'm working with OpenAI Anthropic elements, I know that I am sending the data. Now, they say that they don't share the data with anybody, but really, behind the scenes, what happens? We don't.
PAUL: So, for sensitive type of documents, I will say use doppling unstructured, they are always better.
PAUL: Okay, now, preserving alignment across pages, similarly, like.
PAUL: columns part, if you have that columnar structure, it's really good, because I feel Llama parts will be a very good project in the coming one to two years, because there are a lot of things which are till now missing, that needs to be solved.
PAUL: It's just because we don't have better, layout, models available. Okay, I feel that, yes, with respect to layout…
PAUL: detection. Layout detection is a task in computer vision to analyze the pages. Now, that, the benchmark of those type of tasks right now, they do have higher error rates. Because of those higher error rates, I feel that, yes.
PAUL: With respect to parsing, there can be some type of issues.
PAUL: But probably, as the research goes forward, I can see that the results will be better with respect to time.
PAUL: Aniroth, what to do in these cases? Complex, all you've already told, with respect to complex document.
PAUL: In a document, if you have different type of programming languages embedded, in that case also, it fails a lot.
PAUL: In case.
PAUL: Now, bounding box extraction. Now, I have already told you about bounding boxes. The output of an object detection or a segmentation model is always a bounding box. So, bounding box represents the coordinates, exactly. Where is the location of the image within your document?
PAUL: Okay, now bounding boxes can be based on text also. Okay, now for that particular text, like, a word is there, hello? Now, that… for that particular hello also, you can get a bounding box.
PAUL: All right. Now, bounding box extraction, if you're working with VLMs, VLMs are really good for object detection type of tasks, because behind the scenes, with respect to bounding boxes, it means that some type of object detector model, that always goes around.
PAUL: Now see, here I am passing my custom params.
PAUL: Now, custom params, it means that BB box top, BB box, left, right, and bottom. Now, these are basically the coordinates of the mounting box that we have defined right here.
PAUL: What is the use case of extracting bounding box? Now, if you, like, based on these numbers, you can actually look into a specific part within the image. It's really, totally depends. I don't feel bounding boxes are very, very important. The values are, right now, normalized conditions.
PAUL: But,
PAUL: It means that using these coordinates, you can extract information. It means that, okay, I want to only focus on this particular square or rectangle.
PAUL: In those cases, I feel it's more important.
PAUL: These are simple positions of the image or the object within the document.
PAUL: Bounding box regions, plays a very crucial role in computer vision tasks much more.
PAUL: And here, most of the tasks can be solved using VLMs. Every VLM is capable of doing a detection task.
PAUL: Yes, if you have a QR code, you can detect it simply in QR code also.
PAUL: No issue. And generally, like, setting, these particular positions, you have to really understand the document, and then only you can pass it.
PAUL: Blindly, you cannot set it. So here, baby boxes, top 10% from the top. So, really, you have to play with these parameters. I have just passed a few things for an example, but I feel that to work directly with bounding boxes, it takes more time.
PAUL: Because directly, you cannot get it. Okay, so you have to really play, okay, top 10 here, only for this part of the document that I want you to focus.
PAUL: Okay, so really expensive task.
PAUL: It means that time constraint is towards the higher side.
PAUL: Accessing layout information from different type of razors, so for that extract layout already, Tooled.
PAUL: Now, I think by default, list is coming, if you remember.
PAUL: List is the default one within which you have your texts.
PAUL: Okay, page 1, layout available, okay, based on the layout. The layout information, so within that layout, what are the things which are available? There are text boxes, okay, so then you have column definitions.
PAUL: a reading order, an element classification, like heading, paragraph, table, like, in every type of document, even with markdown, PDF, CS, we'll be having these type of options. So, within a layout, exactly what is the type of information? So, I can say that.
PAUL: Now, really, if you look here.
PAUL: by default, it is telling it true. Okay, true means…
PAUL: In the layout, what are the things that are available?
PAUL: Please let me know this part. This part is important.
PAUL: Because if you look into the code, if result.pages, and I am looking into the first page.
PAUL: Okay? Now, if I change this page for programming, like, if Liz comes into the picture…
PAUL: Actually, it will be better if I get this particular variable here.
PAUL: And you can look into… I'm very specifically looking with hash attribute. Okay, the pay. So, by default, this is being returned as true.
PAUL: And I'm telling that page.layout is not none. It means that it has some type of components, that the components can be heading, paragraph, table. Now, if you want to apply any type of filter operations on top of this, okay, you can manipulate.
PAUL: Always the pages result that you were getting.
PAUL: I really like, with respect to layout.
PAUL: layout-based extraction. It means that only you want to extract headers, only you want to, extract some type of text. In those type of cases, that's important.
PAUL: Now, structured output. Structured output can be based on
PAUL: text, it can be based on Markdown, but as those two options are by default available, so we are focusing on, right now, JSON.
PAUL: Okay, so LamaPars can extract structured data from documents using JSON schemas.
PAUL: Okay, and now for structured output, this is the only parameter that needs to be available. Now, see, this structured output is right now in beta phase.
PAUL: Okay, all the options are not available if I show you in the official documentation. So you can see here, it's pretty much in beta.
PAUL: Okay, so initial JSON support is there, but later on, this structure might change. Okay, and you need to always pass a JSON schema
PAUL: Okay, so, for example, based on a… if you have some type of document through which you can pass a schema, say Python schema, API-based schema, okay, Python preset, I feel that this is more important, so the schema needs to be defined.
PAUL: Some type of predefined schemas, okay, like, while…
PAUL: Card schema that has been provided, then based on invoice-based schema.
PAUL: Okay, really, like, this is somewhere. I don't feel that structured output, always it is very important, but if you know that, yes, I do have these type of
PAUL: Very specific type of, I can say, patterns, okay, within… through which you need the JSON to be extracted. In those cases, only it is important. Otherwise, not so much. Similarly, support is there for resuming.
PAUL: Here's your entire…
PAUL: resume can be passed through a JSON, so the resume schema… so right now, you can look into the… this is a default one which is provided from JSON resume.
PAUL: Properties, label, image, phone, okay, URL. Can you look into the schema? Now, really, now, for every type of resume, this schema won't be available.
PAUL: Now, really, all the information, if somebody is resuming, there is no postal code or country code, nothing that we can do.
PAUL: Profile, work, okay, location, description, position. So, really, this is how exactly your JSON schema looks like. If you feel that you know, okay, and based on that, you can define a schema. Now, this is really good if you feel that in your system, every day only resumes are coming.
PAUL: If you feel that in your system only invoices are coming, then only you can define the schema. Because I can say that, okay, I have a shop. For that shop, I know this is my invoice. Now, based on this particular invoice, I know that this has a certain structure.
PAUL: then it is important. Really, you cannot pass anything in through, directly, okay, to get a structure output. It is not possible.
PAUL: Alright, now something with respect to structured outputs that we have discussed.
PAUL: Okay, now these are some examples, like the wildcard schema that we have presented, then custom schema definition, based on a paper schema, if you feel type, properties, author, description, abstract, keywords, sections.
PAUL: If you're receiving different types of invoices from different type of suppliers, okay, it won't, because the schema needs to be fixed, Shankar. At least you can test it out with 3 different types of invoices, and then you will see that some information will be available, and some won't be.
PAUL: Okay, now for all the documents, we will be actually testing it out.
PAUL: Okay, custom schema-based, okay, now, invoice extraction schema? No, this is just an example that I have provided, really, like, it might work, because a few common fields, like invoice, okay, date, payment due.
PAUL: Sometimes, some other things also that we can apply on top of invoices to get better results, probably some named entities that we have defined. Through that, also, it is possible.
PAUL: Okay, table-based output, so compact markdown table is equal to true. Okay, now, in your final output, okay, you will get a…
PAUL: default, that markdown tag within your Markdown documents through which you can actually get it. Then, HTML table output, this is also possible. So, like, how you want your table to be manipulated, and based on that, what is the output?
PAUL: Okay, now, continuous mode is equal to true. Now, there can be a condition where, okay, your table might run into 5 pages, 6 pages, for those type of conditions, like adapted, long table is equal to true, like multi-pages table. So, yes.
PAUL: options are there, but really, you need to test it out. I feel that this option works good. I have tested it out, okay, and it's really a good option that you can play with. You can take a document, or prepare some type of document, and you can look into the… I can say the parsing is really good.
PAUL: Okay, now, core part, so… now, see, we have discussed so many passes, okay, some might…
PAUL: You might feel a little bit overwhelming, but for now, just remember, stick to one passer.
PAUL: As if you're a beginner, it's a good practice to stick to one.
PAUL: And my favorite is Droplinks.
PAUL: Really, in open source. I might use some structure in some places, it's good, but Dockling, I feel that for every beginner, please do that.
PAUL: And later on, move to Llama parts, because within Llama parts, you don't have a lot of controls, few controls are there, particularly.
PAUL: Not so much. It makes your life easier, it's better, you might get better results, but again, behind the scenes, actually what is going on, I don't know.
PAUL: Okay, so… Now, this part we have done. Now, I'm receiving, okay?
PAUL: What are parsers available in, microsoft.
PAUL: Microsoft process, I don't think anyone is there.
PAUL: There is no such direct Microsoft parallel, as you were telling.
PAUL: Anybody has worked with Microsoft parser? Really, I have not worked with Microsoft Parsals. I don't know whether they have. Because for parsing, I feel the whole organization which is really good is IBM. They work a lot.
PAUL: They do have an other, framework also, referred to as DPK.
PAUL: If, like, DPK is good. DPK? Maybe.
PAUL: This is an actual toolkit, a data preparation toolkit. It is used for RAG, it is used for fine-tuning, a really good project. Anybody has worked with it?
PAUL: Okay, so this is a really good one. But again, like,
PAUL: Little bit advanced, so we're not talking about DPK, but you can actually go through this. It's a really good DPK.
PAUL: Because first, DPK came, and then there were some problems, then Docklings came. Okay, so that's why two different projects are there.
PAUL: Knowledge, so…
PAUL: Now, Azure Document Intelligence? Okay, now that is pretty much an API service, direct parsing service, if I'm talking. Azure Document Intelligence, it has been there for a long, long, long time.
PAUL: The old name was, I think it was Azure Form Recognizer, or something like that, the name was.
PAUL: But it's pretty much that same stuff, with some upgradation, the new talk intelligence type of thing.
PAUL: All right, now… Majorly, so this part is done.
PAUL: Now, if I think we can start discussing a little bit about the project part.
PAUL: If so, project, I think it has…
PAUL: everybody, in the meantime, you can take a clone of the report. Okay, so let's start.
PAUL: Yeah, my in-depth Slacky Monday, I think this is the one.
PAUL: Vectors, we don't. We don't… the API access has been removed already, Mantach. I told about it.
PAUL: If there is no API access, nothing to discuss there.
PAUL: Because the same thing that can be achieved, okay? And in Vectorize, a lot of other things are there, but the core services, Iris, they do have a service there.
PAUL: And majorly, like, I know very few people might be using vectorized. Let's majorly stick to docklinks, unstructured and Llama paths.
PAUL: They are the best solution that we have.
PAUL: Alright, everybody, I've shared it in the chat. Okay, you guys can take a clone of this one.
PAUL: Okay, and first of all, set up the environment.
PAUL: Okay, that is the bare minimum, at least, I feel. I do have a requirement.txt.
PAUL: Like, how many of you worked with me?
PAUL: Make builds, anybody you've worked with, like, C++ make?
PAUL: Because in my projects, I have… now I know Mortasa, I know you use.
PAUL: But really, other than that, Raul Pariah uses, okay, very few people uses it, then.
PAUL: I won't be keeping it.
PAUL: Lumic.
PAUL: Okay, now if you really look into, okay, so which part that you have.
PAUL: That's the most important, I think.
PAUL: This is this particular module, and if you really check, okay, the idea is go-through.
PAUL: Okay, because document processor… okay, these are the only, I think, 5 files that are important, so if you really try to compare them, these are… these are actually the cells of the Jupyter Notebook that I have brought it here.
PAUL: And nothing more, because I want every one of you to focus, because today I won't start the coding part, but when I'll be coding, because a lot of things that are directly taken, like load CSV, load file… Okay, now this is basically a document processor, but once I start coding, I'll be taking only the functions, and I will try to execute them.
PAUL: Okay, because if I try to write line by line this code, it is not possible to do that entire thing. So, every one of you, like, from tomorrow, I will start the main coding part, so please focus on these, because this is the actual thing which is going on within the app.
PAUL: Other than that, whatever the stuff, other things are there in this notebook. Not so much relevant.
PAUL: this Pye files, I feel that you should be very, very familiar.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, read. That's why I have a Readame file always. People who say, okay, so please, go through
PAUL: the core app folder. Other than that, no other folders are so much important.
PAUL: the core RAG work, because everything, if you look into tests, I do have some tests, but really, these tests are not so much important.
PAUL: Because just for the purpose of keeping some test cases, I have kept it.
PAUL: your CI CD pipeline, people who are interested, okay, you can look into the workflows file. Okay, so I think your CI.YML, this is your main integration with GitHub Actions. Okay, because few people from other batches, they can actually decode the entire stuff.
PAUL: It's pretty much standard.
PAUL: But for a few, it might be new, so the idea is that to focus that entire ecosystem, it's not only one thing, but what are the other things that can? Because in every project, we'll be maintaining such a structure.
PAUL: If you look into the OpenAI API key, have I provided, .env.example. So, here, few parameters that you can keep it. So, right here, you can see OpenAI, and here I have even done the integration with Langsmith.
PAUL: thought about using something, so this time Landsmith, next time I might switch to pick monitoring. So, these things I will keep on changing. So for you guys, if you are taking a clone of this one.
PAUL: Okay, please be sure you pass your keys, your quadrant URL, your quadrant API key, and I think everybody can create. Please let me know, people with quadrant.
PAUL: Okay? Quadrant, your pictures go to the website, you have to do a sign-up operation, and you have to fetch those things. So if I do a login.
PAUL: should add .getignore to avoid .envs when we checked in. Yes, correct. Always you should do that.
PAUL: Because few API keys, okay, so probably…
PAUL: Okay, so once you create a new cluster here, in Quadrant, everybody, please do it today. Tomorrow, I don't want you guys to waste time on these type of things. But at least by today, please fix these things. Okay, your API keys, I think everybody has an OpenAI API key.
PAUL: Otherwise, if you want to switch with Gemini and others, okay, because…
PAUL: This is entirely built on the OpenAI. Okay, so probably we might need to change in the code.
PAUL: Okay, so just create a cluster, use AWS, Azure, everything is there. Okay, cluster details, and based on that.
PAUL: Okay, I… because I already have created a cluster. Okay, so free cluster, I think you can create only one.
PAUL: So, the free tile. So, everybody, please do create a free cluster today, and once you have created it, if I show you, okay, you will be getting the cluster ID and the endpoint. So, this endpoint is the quadrant TY that you will be using.
PAUL: Okay, so very, very important, this endpoint that you have, you need to pass it in your
PAUL: I can say into this particular URL.
PAUL: And the API key, it will be shown to you only once, so during the creation, please copy-paste that key.
PAUL: Okay, so just be sure your API key will be accessible only once, so please take a copy of that.
PAUL: Now, I'm not going to use… or see, people who want to use different LLMs, you need to do the configuration in that way.
PAUL: Make the project public.
PAUL: Who is telling the project is not public?
PAUL: Can you see it here?
PAUL: So, really, people are telling the project is not public.
PAUL: And, see guys, with respect to the EY part, okay, really, this thing, I have not tested it yet.
PAUL: Okay, so a few things are there that I am working on, but I think UI should not be a priority.
PAUL: Yeah, the core idea is to building the backend part.
PAUL: Okay, so… uv.logged static, I think inside the static folder, I have some UI files.
PAUL: Please let me know, have you guys taken the clone? Are you guys setting up the .envy?
PAUL: Don't share the API game Muntas or Rothi.
PAUL: Okay, it's fine you are sharing with me, but really, keep it to yourself. I don't want your API keys and all those.
PAUL: Quadrant, what can you tell? Again, go to website.
PAUL: Okay, Quadrant, do you want me to create a new account? Let me see, just wait.
PAUL: I do have the…
PAUL: Boop.
PAUL: AWS accounts, like, real AWS is not needed. Next day, by next week, just be sure you are having that.
PAUL: We have sent an email, Jay, let me just check the email one.
PAUL: 119…
PAUL: Yes, I'm going to use.
PAUL: Langsmith. Okay, and you will see everyone, please look here. You will see something like this, create a free cluster.
PAUL: Everybody, please do a sign up, and just be sure you have that quadrant cloud. So here, I will pass a name, something like Project, anything you can pass it here. Okay, I don't use Google Cloud a lot, I will be using AWS.
PAUL: And the nearest region that I have is… Brantford.
PAUL: Alright, Frankfurt works for me.
PAUL: Okay, project, VDB?
PAUL: Something like this. Now I'll click on Create Cluster.
PAUL: Okay, now you will see this API key that I'm showing you, it will be shown to me only once. So this you need to copy. Okay, so one is this particular API key, and then is… this is the endpoint that you have. Two things that you need to copy.
PAUL: Please have a check.
PAUL: Yes, I'll be doing the entire coding.
PAUL: Right now, I'm telling you, at least set up the environment today, so that you don't have any problems going forward.
PAUL: Should we do a top-up? I will be using OpenAI. You can take my code, and you can always switch and change the LN.
PAUL: There is no issue.
PAUL: AWS… AWS is the next thing, because AWS part will come probably next week. For tomorrow's class, it is not important. If you have not created your accounts, you have one week of time.
PAUL: next Saturday or Sunday, when we'll be working only on the deployment part, then cloud is required.
PAUL: Right now, cloud is not required, so everyone just be sure you have the API key and the cluster endpoint wiki.
PAUL: Okay, so take your time, spend 5 minutes, not a big deal, but at least do it today. In tomorrow's setup, please don't ask me to do that.
PAUL: I'll be doing coding from scratch only, yes. I have shared one file. I think I have shared a template file with you.
PAUL: I don't remember, do I have… thisTemplate.py.
PAUL: So, we will start from this. I do have shared this template. Using this template, entire folder structure and other things that will be created for you.
PAUL: But there will be few components, for example, if I'm talking with respect to UI, UI part, I will never discuss.
PAUL: Only the AI part, that I'll be focusing much more.
PAUL: Okay, because there are a lot of things. Now, a few people might say, I don't do GitHub action.
PAUL: Now, really, I am not here to teach you GitHub Actions.
PAUL: I hope you guys understand, okay? Because when I show you a full ecosystem, in that ecosystem, there can be a lot of things.
PAUL: Okay. So, out of that, you have to just pick up, okay, I'm using for these type of tasks.
PAUL: What will be the use for Langsman? Just for observability purpose. Whatever the things and the conversation will go on, I will just, throw it to Langsman. That's the only stuff.
PAUL: prepare for Ulama, okay, so one thing you can do, sit tonight, do the changes for Ulla.
PAUL: I think you people can do it with respect to the changes in OLAMA.
PAUL: Okay, so take this piece of code, and then you have to change the part. And probably with respect to, I think, you have to pass it through your
PAUL: Config.py, this is the actual file for passing all your settings. So, from here, like, you can add a particular configuration.
PAUL: Because for Ulama, you really don't need to, but you can pass some type of model name, and you can actually call it in your main chain.
PAUL: Okay, so those type of changes that you can do, because by default, my entire configuration will be based on OpenAI. Later on, I will play with Anthropic, sometimes Coher.
PAUL: But much more. So, free stuff I won't be using, so please be sure, or change your L&Ms.
PAUL: Don't worry, right now I'm just telling you the things that are important.
PAUL: From tomorrow, I will start the, like, scratch coding entirely.
PAUL: But this will be your main thing I'll be taking. It means that when I take a copy-paste.
PAUL: The code for a certain file, just be sure you… Are comfortable with this one.
PAUL: Anurag is telling, please let all the things that are done in production, all the things that are not possible. Nobody will tell you, neither teach you.
PAUL: In production, it might take 6 months, so, like, I cannot tell you everything. I will just say the poor focus parts only.
PAUL: Because, one project only I've kept it hard, the third project.
PAUL: Because to work on projects, it takes really a long time.
PAUL: You know, the structure, this is my structure right now, really, it's not important. Like, I have kept it, otherwise, if it's a module or a package, if I feel, I can keep it within the SRC.
PAUL: So it's totally up to you.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: See, structure, you can define it. It's not necessary that I'm using the structure.
PAUL: My structure is totally, like, you can play with this. Everything should be modular structure, that's the core idea. If it's a packager that you are developing, please use SRC. It's a simple application using different frameworks, you can use app. There is no restriction.
PAUL: If it's a package, I prefer using SRC machine, but right now, that's why you don't…
PAUL: Because it's not a package that I'm developing.
PAUL: Now, Suhaj is asking, there are two requirements, fine. Only use requirement.th.
PAUL: How many of you know the meaning of two requirements?
PAUL: Because this is Pythony, this is nothing related to AI.
PAUL: Can you show your cluster configuration?
PAUL: My cluster configuration is here.
PAUL: Really, I can't close this. If I close this, everything will be deleted.
PAUL: Words to install? Look into the requirement.txt file, and based on that, do the installation.
PAUL: This is your quadrant setup. It's a one-time thing. Two things, the cluster endpoint and the API key.
PAUL: I'll be using everything from OpenAI Sonali.
PAUL: Yes, Mama. Today, I won't be starting the project. The idea is that three major things that you should do today, okay? One is setting up the environment, okay?
PAUL: So, the first one that I feel is, please, environment setup. Don't tell me I'm having installation issue. Spend some time today, complete the environment setup.
PAUL: Once the environment setup is, done, then with respect to your ENV variables.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just write it here virtually, and…
PAUL: Okay, and then virtual ENV, this is your ENV variables.
PAUL: Okay, so probably, I think, for quadrant, that is the most important one.
PAUL: Please do the setup.
PAUL: It really doesn't matter, Zary and Gupta. Choose your nearest place.
PAUL: Tonal is asking, it asks to choose what you want to do, search simple. For now, simple, keep it simple. We are not discussing hybrid or anything.
PAUL: Do I need to select Google? You can select anything, doesn't matter, whichever cloud.
PAUL: Okay, so no restrictions there. Select the one that you love, whether you love GCP, whether you love AWS.
PAUL: Okay, now, okay, you need one more variable, which is the Lang Smith one.
PAUL: Before Lance Meth… Let me show you that one. You just need to create the API and nothing more.
PAUL: US Central, I will prefer EU much more.
PAUL: So this is a part where you can actually create your API keys.
PAUL: And you have to always remember this, like, whether you are using US Central or not, okay? For Langsmith directly, this is the only thing that you require.
PAUL: And always remember, you are going with Eva Central or UVC.
PAUL: Only two things. Other than that, nothing is required.
PAUL: Langsmith for tracking, nothing I am doing tracking. I was just doing tracing.
PAUL: You're not.
PAUL: Only one thing, you need the API key and nothing more.
PAUL: Okay, so you will be getting your API keys directly here, so go to Settings, and based on that, you will get it.
PAUL: Who will you decide to.
PAUL: So please go to Settings, okay, then API keys, and please create your API keys.
PAUL: Endpoint, it totally depends. During sign-up, you have selected EU or not. I have selected EU, so based on that, I have selected.
PAUL: Okay, so if I want… see, at any point of time, if you feel that what are the things according to your configuration.
PAUL: Okay, please click on this particular option, you will get the entire… So, first of all, click on Tracing Projects.
PAUL: tracing, then click on New Project, and you will get automatically, as you can see here, dependencies.
PAUL: the Langchain and Langchain OpenAI, and these are the environment variables that you have.
PAUL: And you will get only two things. This, the third one, API key, that you need to pass, and the OpenAI API key. The rest, the same thing that you have to do.
PAUL: Okay, now, versions part, really. You can remove all the versions from your requirement.txt based on that pre-string.
PAUL: Because I always share my requirement.txt.
PAUL: Langsmith part, guys, done, because directly you can copy-paste it from here.
PAUL: And this project name, you can pass anything.
PAUL: Okay, so it's really not important if you can't change these things. So, directly copy-paste everything
PAUL: And paste it in your .env file.
PAUL: Other than that, I think only two things are important.
PAUL: Your quadrant setup.
PAUL: Collection name, really doesn't matter, log label, API host, API port, and okay?
PAUL: Rest, nothing… okay, next, we can start, basically, the discussion with respect to the Bridget.
PAUL: people getting installation issues, please resolve. If somebody is getting module not found error by this time, the idea is that you should know that for which module you are getting this.
PAUL: If you do not, otherwise, please ask in the doubt class.
PAUL: Take the personal access token, Mammoth.
PAUL: How do I check mine?
PAUL: API and function to URL, as simple as that, or here also, you will be getting
PAUL: By default, it will be showing for everyone, it's not like that it's showing for me, it will be showing for you also. Please check.
PAUL: Yes, people who want to drop, they can drop. People who are advanced users, you know, few people are here, pretty much advanced, so they can drop, no issues. But others, please do the setup tomorrow. I won't be spending the time only in the installation and environment setup.
PAUL: I will start from a scratch report as well.
PAUL: Yes, mine one is showing eu.smith.clanchain. Yes, look into the URL.
PAUL: Look into my URL. My URL is based on eui.smithLanchay.
PAUL: Use any region, Prashan, no restriction. Use US Central, use EU used.
PAUL: Okay, EU waste is also fine, I have no problem with that.
PAUL: Sampa 3 is asking in Langsmith.
PAUL: Tracing projects, how to get keys. Now, only I showed you, example, how to get the keys.
PAUL: Just search in Google Langsmith, do a sign-up, go to Settings, there will be an API key which is available.
PAUL: Everybody, please look here, one second.
PAUL: Once you have done the sign-up, you will get something like this, okay?
PAUL: the first thing is you get an ABI key. Click on Settings.
PAUL: Click on API key, click on Personal Access Token, select, like, default. If there is nothing, I think the default workspace that comes here.
PAUL: Okay, 30 days or something like that.
PAUL: iPhone?
PAUL: And let me pass something like class.
PAUL: Now, this is the API key that I have created. Just be sure you save this API key. Done.
PAUL: Now, next, go to works, I think. I will go to projects.
PAUL: Here, click on New Project. Tracing projects under, you will be getting New Project. And from here, you'll be getting all the information. Please do
PAUL: this.
PAUL: Alright, Sanjay, fine. You can do it, I know Murta can do it, you people can do it. No…
PAUL: issued.
PAUL: Show me the environment script where I need to define the Langsmith?
PAUL: quadrant key. It will be in your .env file, I think everybody knows where you have to do it.
PAUL: After creating the API key, where to go?
PAUL: Where to go, it means that you have to update your .env file, guys.
PAUL: These are some bare minimum Pythonic requirements. There is no such complex stuff.
PAUL: I have already shared my .env.example, so create your .env.
PAUL: In every class, I am sharing my .env.example, so I think by this time, you guys should be familiar
PAUL: That, okay, you have to just take a copy of this file and then update the variable width.
PAUL: Leave, if it is not showing US Central, it is fine. Go, not a big problem.
PAUL: Select your nearest place. That's why I selected Europe.
PAUL: Langsmith project, nor Rahul Parihar. We cannot project…
PAUL: Later on, it will be created during the execution. Why you want to create it now?
PAUL: During the execution, automatically lands, when it gets detected, it will create the project during runtime. Nothing that we have to do.
PAUL: Nobody needs to create an end point.
PAUL: It will provide you the endpoint.
PAUL: Aren't we adding evils? Yes, Ragas is there.
PAUL: Check the code, check the code, at least read the README part, people, before asking questions.
PAUL: Please check this part.
PAUL: This is the… your main tech stack.
PAUL: So take your time, no. I'm not telling, ask questions directly. Take your time, go through, and then ask.
PAUL: There's not that…
PAUL: Take your time. That's why I'm giving you time. Like, that's why I shared the report today only, so at least you people can go through.
PAUL: And many of you can do an execution also.
PAUL: Gemini, no, my code is not configured. Very specifically, you need to change a few things. When we'll be doing the coding, I'll be showing you that you can change this part if you want to switch to Gemini, or some other stuff.
PAUL: Docker Desktop, Tomorrow, not needed. Next week, it is needed.
PAUL: I think on Saturday or Sunday next week, not today.
PAUL: E2317 is asking difference between two requirements files, one for dev, one for product.
PAUL: Quadrant URL, cluster endpoints are same. Know how it can be same. Right now, I just showed you.
PAUL: It cannot be seen, no?
PAUL: I think somewhere. One will be your endpoint.
PAUL: And, the API key, once you have created it, it will show you the API key. Please go through that.
PAUL: At, personal access token.
PAUL: She was.
PAUL: Quadrant, URL, and cluster. Okay, the variables are you talking about? Okay, so please check the variable names can be different, but I feel that, inside my.env.example.
PAUL: This endpoint is the URL, okay? The end point is the URL.
PAUL: whatever that HTTPS link that will give, that is actually work.
PAUL: Okay, endpoint is URL, don't get confused.
PAUL: Raul, it's working for you, great.
PAUL: Just be sure, see, in my requirements, there can be specific versions that I have mentioned. In your case, remove the versions, if you feel that, if there is some type of installation issue. I think I already have removed, but only for Radhas, I was aware that 0.3.7.
PAUL: And length 0.4.55. Other than that, okay, I've already removed, so I don't think…
PAUL: Installation will be problematic for anyone. Please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: You don't need to run the code.
PAUL: Running the code is not there.
PAUL: Because, regarding the EY, again, I don't remember the EY fixes.
PAUL: If somebody's asking the question, UI leave, the UI part right now will be majorly focused on the back-end part.
PAUL: You don't need to run any code, MS.
PAUL: influential.
PAUL: I'm using OpenAI. Later on, when we'll be doing the project, I'll be telling you. If we want to go with Gemini, you can change this part and this part.
PAUL: then you can do the configuration test, okay? I'm not restricting, only use OpenAI. You don't want to use OpenAI, it's fine. Just be sure that during our discussion, when I'll be writing the code, okay, so at that particular point of time, you please update that particular, thing.
PAUL: If the ENV file is updated, great. Only that two things, please do it today. That is the request, because with respect to project and everything, I will explain, but at least, I think these two things, the virtual environment setup.
PAUL: and the E&B variables. Please do it today. Tomorrow, we won't be spending time. Directly, we will jump into the project. The project is really big. Okay, so the idea is that, going forward, the other project that I'll be discussing, you should be fine with that.
PAUL: Don't worry, for tracing in every framework, it's just one line of code, Jonas. When I'll be talking about Landsmith, I'll be talking there.
PAUL: Landsmith is not, like, a big technology that you need to understand.
PAUL: Okay? So during the languagement discussion, I'll be talking about it.
PAUL: No, please don't use your existing virtual environments, only create No, okay.
PAUL: For every project, the idea is that you should have isolated environment guides.
PAUL: Don't mix the environments.
PAUL: Alright, I've taken… Just repeat.
PAUL: Which Python version, 3.12 is fine, I think 3.12, no more issues.
PAUL: Okay,
PAUL: Okay, Srinath, after creating the new project in Langspace, I don't see the project. Don't worry, you don't have to create any project now.
PAUL: Okay? Please don't create the project. During our execution, it will be automatically created, please don't worry about that.
PAUL: Customer is asking, can I… Yeah, the Landsmith endpoint, correct, Asuna. Only that EU Smith, that is correct.
PAUL: able to launch. People who are doing it, they will know that they will be able to launch localhost 8000 slash docs. Okay.
PAUL: S12, yes, 3.12.4 is fine, I have no issues. Just be sure your Python version is at least above 3.11. That is a bare minimum requirement.
PAUL: Landsmith project name, the name of the project, whatever you can pass it. Rag, project, queue project.
PAUL: How much OpenAI credit will be needed?
PAUL: See, generally, I think the minimum is $5 or $6 that you can do at top-up.
PAUL: Okay, because I think $6 for this entire course, $6 will be…
PAUL: Even it will be left after the course, because every time you won't be using OpenAI,
PAUL: If you want, you can do the bare minimum flex term.
PAUL: Could not get Langsmith Endpoint.
PAUL: Arun, how… the Langsmith endpoint, you will be getting it.
PAUL: Whenever you click on this option.
PAUL: Of a new project, by default, you will be getting this one.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: You'll be getting the endpoint automatically here.
PAUL: create virtual environment, then do git clone. Yes, you can do before that also, Shanti, or after that. It's totally up to your workflow definition, how you do it, first or second.
PAUL: There is no such priority in that.
PAUL: It's… is it necessary to have OpenAI key to work with Landsmith? No, no, no, no.
PAUL: Mitesh, there is no OpenAI and Langesmith dependency, it's totally independent.
PAUL: You can use any TA, like, Gemini is also free.
PAUL: Thor, Onda, remove the version, Armani.
PAUL: Okay, for conduct, please remove the version of Blanksmith that I have in mind, okay, and use whatever the recent version that you were getting.
PAUL: Okay, Rajat, I will come, okay?
PAUL: Let's… Todd, taking question is going to be 12.
PAUL: Rahul Bahir, what about ECR repository? Those things, configuration, I'll be talking about, the day we start about Cloud Route. Because, yes, ECR repository, AWS, CLI setup.
PAUL: Those things in future classes, not today.
PAUL: And I will try to make it through commands much more as compared to EY.
PAUL: So that it becomes easier. You create a user, you give it the admin access, and based on that.
PAUL: Easily to make it.
PAUL: Okay, fine. Shankar Rocha, this is fine. There is no problem. Your endpoint looks good.
PAUL: It's the correct URL.
PAUL: Alright, now…
PAUL: I think Rajat is there. Rajat, you want to go ahead? Okay, Murthaza is there. Let me take some technical… Murthaza, you can go.
Murtuza Saifee: Hi, hi, Paul.
PAUL: Yes.
Murtuza Saifee: Hope you're doing well. First of all, I want to take, like, 10-15 seconds to thank you, because this session is really going great, all the sessions, and
Murtuza Saifee: And the amount of the things that you're teaching on the architecture level and the things is really helpful. It's helping, like, at least me a lot on these things.
Murtuza Saifee: Just, one thing, I just want to comment the question quickly.
Murtuza Saifee: So… I have…
Murtuza Saifee: Recently, we just, gone to, into production internal one, Terraform system, Terraform Agent.
Murtuza Saifee: That we have live in production, internal.
PAUL: Last time I told no, during the.
Murtuza Saifee: Yeah.
PAUL: batch of Agent Dinghi were working on. Correct, correct.
Murtuza Saifee: Yeah, so we just live pushed into the production. Now, that… this is for our DevOps team. It automates some of our lower environmental dev and stage pipelines and the flows for our Terraform on the AWS.
Murtuza Saifee: So, recently, we, discussed the RAG evaluation. So, I want to do the evaluation of that agent as well. So.
Murtuza Saifee: Can vagas be the fit over there, or…
PAUL: Ragas is much more for RAG part that has been only created. You can switch to, like, deep events, their few metrics are available. Arise AI, their few metrics are available, very specifically for agent evaluation.
Murtuza Saifee: Because this will be, again, will be a very subjective evolution. So…
PAUL: I got your point.
Murtuza Saifee: So, what I'm thinking, I'll just take another 30 seconds for this one. So, what I'm thinking is just to, so we do have, of course, the Terraform pieces that we have set as an GTs, right? So, because we know what are the exact Terraform pieces that can come.
Murtuza Saifee: So, I'm thinking to use those, and then ingest into as an, you know, evaluation dataset, the same thing that we… you showed us.
Murtuza Saifee: The same way I'm thinking it to… yeah, to compare this with what my agent is producing. So…
Murtuza Saifee: I will try it out. I might will face some blockers, I might will need some of your guidance if I face it. But, so this is what I'm thinking on.
PAUL: Alright, on top of where I got your point. Last time you told me you have not done the evaluation.
Murtuza Saifee: Yes.
PAUL: Holy…
Murtuza Saifee: Fuck.
Murtuza Saifee: Okay, that's it from my side, Paul. Again, thank you so much.
PAUL: Yeah, iPhone? Yeah, Rajat.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so my first, question is related to VLLM.
Rajat Khanna: So, as in using a multimodal rag, so…
PAUL: is related to VLM or VLLM?
Rajat Khanna: VLLM.
PAUL: Okay, brilliant. Yeah.
Rajat Khanna: And, while means currently we were working on naive racks, so in the advanced rack, there will be multimodal racks.
Rajat Khanna: So in multimodal, so it's like we, LLM, we are using one single model, which have a support of multimodal, only one model we will be integrating, and it will be supporting multiple models, or we…
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: See, simple, like, when you talk about two types of models, if I'm referring, unimodals only works with text, and multimodals means it can work with audio, radio, any type of stuff. Both the LLMs are totally different. One LLM is the Unimodals, the other one is basically multimodal.
Rajat Khanna: It's multimodal, not multi-model.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, got it. Because I'm confusing, like, we will be using different models, as in, only one is for text, one is for audio-video, one is for some… another. So I was, I was thinking, like, we will be using 3 LLM models in one simple rack.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no. Okay. Don't make it so much. See, generally in RAD, okay, you can use… because in VLMs, okay, now, as you told, like, VLLM, that is different. VLLM is totally different. It is used for serving LLM. That's a totally different topic. That's why I asked you, VLM or VLM.
Rajat Khanna: VLLM is totally separate, so you are asking much more towards only vision language models.
PAUL: Visual language models can handle text.
PAUL: As well as images, okay, so that's why you really don't need… if you're using VLF, it means that by default, everything will be taken care of.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
PAUL: But if it is only text-based models, okay, then it becomes a problem, because it cannot work with images.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so for, like, simple example, like, we are using ChatGPT, so it is one single model which can deal with audio, images, photographic, text, all those things.
PAUL: Much more of a service under the hood.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, under the…
PAUL: It means that for images, probably, yes, it might be calling a different model. For simple text operations, it might be calling a different model.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, so, yeah, so this was the main question, like, there will be a one single model who can deal with text, image, and audio, and there can be other models as well, other RAG models as well, which will be calling. If it is a text, then one… this LLM will be called.
PAUL: RAG as a model. That's the thing. See?
PAUL: only two com- two model features that comes. One is that LLM, that is one model that we do refer. The other one is an embedding. Only two things. Now, in the LLM, if you want an image-based support, then for that is VLMs that comes in, like GPT-4, something like that. But always remember, the…
PAUL: token cost for VRMs are, like.
PAUL: More than 4x to 5x times much costlier.
Rajat Khanna: No, in the Python programming, like, if I, the condition, like, if it is a text, then use this model. If this is a audio, then use this model, like, like this bifurcation.
PAUL: No, generally, like, VLMs can handle automatically text also, no. You can make for cost optimization that, okay, for text only, like, only.
PAUL: on top of text, you can do this. If you want a VLM support, then separately another LLM call that will be. So, you have to make that class, within that class, with that multi-LLM
PAUL: Class you need to create, and based on that conditional logic that you can keep it.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, and other question is related to kernel crash, so that one code snippet, import OS and that, you shared, right?
PAUL: bias, that is mostly.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay. No, because I was using some another code snippets, so I'm just using basic M1 error, so sometime, if the high computation is there, the kernel also crashes.
Rajat Khanna: So, if I do multiple, cells in one single cell, then it done exactly fine. But if there are multiple cells, like normally we have our, Jupyter node.
PAUL: Jupyter notebooks.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so in multiple cell, if I do it, so it crashes. So, that was the issue.
PAUL: Alright, generally what happens, the main error of bundle crash happens due to multiple instantiation.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, of the theme object.
PAUL: That is the main reason in files that happen. And in Jupyter Notebook, that's the main problem.
PAUL: Okay, if you work it in Python scripts, you won't feel that issue.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay. And my last question is related to somewhat, a career graph, as I'm already 10 years of experience into front-end.
Rajat Khanna: So I'm making a transition into, you, this AI, gen AI engineer. So, while my… I might not get internal, project, and I will be trying to change the organization based on all this RAG and basic understanding of.
Rajat Khanna: whatever the topics you are teaching, and all the basic AI that we need to know. So, is that sufficient to make a transition, or do we need to learn some.
PAUL: Your level of experience is really high.
Rajat Khanna: So…
PAUL: For you, it's not only, you have to… Understand the other components also.
PAUL: like, it's, directly, I cannot say only GenAI will help, because this is right now in Gen AI, and then this course is highly focused towards only one component that I have.
PAUL: The LLM component, we won't be discussing. So, I feel that you should explore a little bit of that LLM part also, where you should know what type of quantization that you want to do, if you want to fine-tune on top of a small data set. Those type of tasks, at least, hands-on that you need to do.
PAUL: You probably need to spend close to, like, $100 in AWS. The idea is that be good in at least one cloud. Whichever cloud you are good in previously. If you are good in Azure, stick to Azure, continue all of your work. The idea is to know much more AI-related services in those respective clouds.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, so while I'm doing the certification in the ML-AWS course, so whatever that ML-AWS course includes, I need to be perfect in that one single day.
PAUL: Speciality, there is an AWS MU speciality, I know, certification is there.
Rajat Khanna: Yes.
PAUL: which covers the basics and majorly all the services which will be used. You can… I think it has two different versions associated.
Rajat Khanna: Yes, yes, I'm currently doing the associate one.
PAUL: Alright, that will give you an idea, at least. If you're sticking to AWS, then it's easy.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, because, my, my main question is, like, currently,
PAUL: In front end, like, you have worked with React, Next.js, these type of frameworks, no?
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, Angular and Express.
PAUL: Okay, Angular is also fine. It will be easy only, because… because, see, here, in this course, at least I know that by the end of this course, you guys will be good in backend.
PAUL: Now, logic part and other things, really, UI I don't think about. My main job is to do the containerization, and then the UI team uses those APIs. As simple as that. Okay, so in your case also, same thing. Like, you know that UI part. Yes. Now, exposing those, you know that easily it can be handled.
PAUL: But focus on one cloud, okay, at least one dB, because at least as we will be talking with respect to the project. So, what project you are planning.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, to say, and how is that storytelling.
PAUL: if you let me know those things, it will be better. Then at least I can say that, okay, for this particular domain in this way. So, I'll cross-portioning, if I do at least a cross-portioning, it will help me. So, at least let me know, and even with your latest resume, it dropped, drop to me, I mean.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, no, so means, that, conversation we can have later, because there are other person in queue, but my.
PAUL: The easy thing is, right now, I'm not telling you. First, drop me a mail, then first I have to evaluate your resume, and then probably I can ask you for a one-to-one call. Basically, for these two questions, I cannot do it in public.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, okay, I'll connect with you later for the day. Thank you, thank you, Paul.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Next, Nitesh, Rahul Parihar, Akel, Roy Silvasta, Dig Vijay, Amitsa. Okay, many people are unmuted, so one word running past.
Rahul Parihar: So, Paul, first question is, with the latest changes, you know, like,
Rahul Parihar: One is the DeepSeek OCR. So they… they come up with this concept that… Text.
Rahul Parihar: To image conversion, and shortening the context size With understanding of the images.
Rahul Parihar: how… That dimension will change.
Rahul Parihar: The complete context.
PAUL: Like, see, Deep OCR, deep-seq OCR I've not used, but with respect to attention mechanism, few things have been changed in that particular architecture. Really, I've not gone deep dive, okay, into that one, but really, like, if you want, you can let me know, then I will explore and then tell it, that part.
PAUL: Because exactly with respect to dimensionality, it means that I have to go through the academic paper once, then only I can let you.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, and related to the project, if I'm hitting my local health ready, and it's saying.
Rahul Parihar: A name of the project rack document, status is green, that means the endpoint is working, right?
PAUL: If, yes, if your slash docs is opening, it means that, and even…
PAUL: Because if you have configured also, then you can test out the…
PAUL: endpoints that you are. Okay, all the routes of… you can test it, because I think major routes are… one is uploading that document, then there is a query.
PAUL: I think streaming responses… Yeah, a few things are there, even I don't exactly remember, but I feel that you can test it out if you have configured those settings in Neo.envp.
Rahul Parihar: Got it.
PAUL: Only your CI build will fail with respect to GitHub.
PAUL: That part.
Rahul Parihar: And I'm trying to understand the core, project overview. What is the project all about? Like.
PAUL: See, in this project.
PAUL: It's a very, very simple project. The idea is to get new people out here. See, you… I know your experience is quite good, but there are a few people who don't know about CICD pipelines also.
PAUL: Okay, adding a few test cases, okay, passing it through multiple tests and continuous integration, those type. Rank part, it's pretty much simple. I told you, within the app folder, you will see 5 files. Those 5 files are really important.
PAUL: If you want to increase the complexity, I've showed you the other report, Project 2, where I've taken one AI, text-to-SQL, those type of tasks. If you want to next level, there I think your routing also I have applied. I don't… I have not applied semantic routing, I think logical routing is there.
PAUL: But in that third project, I think semantic routing also I've added. So, you can.
Rahul Parihar: slowly.
PAUL: each…
Rahul Parihar: Yeah.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, main issue that I'm facing in my application is on the semantic routing, whether routing to relational database and graph DBs, vector score is fine, you know, but…
Rahul Parihar: Deciding which data source to point to.
Rahul Parihar: And based on the context of the question, it should logically, you know, semantically route to those data sources.
Rahul Parihar: That logic is not working, and there is a concept of corrective rag, you know.
PAUL: CRAG, Adaptive REG in your syllabus also, I think after Landra, we'll be talking about those.
Rahul Parihar: Will talking about.
PAUL: CRAG, yes, CGRAG, AdaptiveRag. Yes, from there only, I think. Yes, it has the paper also, research paper is also there.
Rahul Parihar: So we… can we fork this document and create a pull request for you, like, if we have some suggestions?
PAUL: Really, for this one, daily.
Rahul Parihar: Not disciplined, yeah.
PAUL: You can… what you can do.
PAUL: Just wait, let me start sharing, and here, with respect to GitHub.
Rahul Parihar: Like, can you… can you provide, like, people who would like to contribute what areas you like?
PAUL: See, if I'm talking about right now, see, I know most of the students from Batch, very few people, less than 50 people, who can do that. I can take, for that, I was planning.
PAUL: Just wait, let me open my various taya, just wait. Okay, here. So, in my repositories, okay, so let me just remove data parsers.
PAUL: See, in this hybrid ride, I will be taking that, because I feel this project is more important.
PAUL: Because this will be a big project. So here.
PAUL: I think somewhere in Gox or somewhere.
PAUL: I think future announcement, this part I have taken.
PAUL: Okay, now, really, these are all possible type of things that can be done.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the part, because I am actually working on this one, I've not segregated exactly, because few functionalities are not related to AI, and few functionalities are related to AI. So AI-related part, if anybody has at least, like, 5 to 6 hours a week, then I'll be taking the contribution, because at least the idea is that few people get used to.
PAUL: Okay, so, okay, so, see, really, like, prompt injection, okay, really, with respect to guardrails, advancements, everything that can be done here.
PAUL: So I've really kept at the long detail of advanced rack capabilities, and right now, agentic rack workflows, so that part you can work on. So, really, land graphs.
PAUL: Once we have discussed land corrupt then only. So, I have planned that, but I feel that people can do it a little bit later. I feel that after one month, or starting from next year. Once they are familiar with the starting two projects, and they are good, people who are having experience have no issue.
PAUL: I will… like, you can do that. You can take a fork, you can raise a PR,
PAUL: Okay, because I have to add that few testing part, that is the main thing, few test cases.
PAUL: With respect to linting, and a few things are there. Because this project, like, I will suggest you go through this one. For others, I won't suggest this hybrid such app.
PAUL: And check the field-wise commit, because I've created a field twice.
PAUL: Okay, so look into every thesis, and then…
Rahul Parihar: Boop.
PAUL: Only for you, I'm suggesting this.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, Paul, I would… one… there are two things, you know, just to close on this. This is really, really, very cutting edge, and I'll tell you, I've been talking to other people in US,
Rahul Parihar: The same amount of training that you're providing.
Rahul Parihar: They're charging $10,000, you know.
PAUL: I know, I know.
Rahul Parihar: So, no…
PAUL: I know people from AWS just for 8 classes. Like, I don't know, how many of you know about me, even?
Rahul Parihar: music.
PAUL: Megan, you know, like, it's common, like, $2,000 a count, but, like, Indian market.
PAUL: Okay, I know, like, when I say $200 or something, I know most of that, I can say, like.
PAUL: People having 3 to 4 years of experience, they are ready to pay that tomorrow.
PAUL: But for a fresher and others, $200, they might think that… high course.
Rahul Parihar: No, no, this is really… this is really appreciable, guys, you know, the effort that Chris and you guys are putting into training is really good.
Rahul Parihar: I would like to, just call out this, that I'm part of a startup project where I'm putting up a generative AI engine rule, and we are upscaling a lot right now.
Rahul Parihar: So, do you have option to do consulting on a generative AI space, on my product space, especially?
PAUL: Bank does a lot of consulting, because I'm towards a little bit of development, much more.
PAUL: bank is not available, then only I do his part with respect to consultation.
PAUL: Previously, we have done it, because right now, Kesh is focused in the next two to three months, there are a lot of launches, like ZenoDocs, then that resume a platform. Three to four different platforms will be launched.
PAUL: And then there will be that projects part, although, like, if you know previously, there was a platform called us Projects Pro. Okay, based on that, like, multiple projects, very specific to this, so that part that we are working, because for that, again, I have to create the content record.
PAUL: So, initial, like, I feel that till February, my timeline is pretty much high.
PAUL: After that, if you want very specific request, you can directly drop a question to me. Okay, because last time also, I will let you know at least, if it is there.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah.
PAUL: See, at the end of the day, your use case matters, like, if you share the use case, then I will look into that. Then, probably, if you want, I can take Trish also. But the use case, like, if it is interesting, because.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, one… one is the product side. I would definitely like to engage you. Another is the open source side, where I have submitted a DeepMind, idea in ed tech domain, to Google, you know, Google Kaggle program. So I'll send you that, program link.
Rahul Parihar: I've just submitted the document with the proof-of-concept code, you know, so I'd just like to take your views.
Rahul Parihar: how to give back to the community, you know, a rack system with an AI tutor program that is much needed, so…
Rahul Parihar: I'm looking for some guidance there.
PAUL: that could be great. Even for schools also, like, we have specific RAG system for Class 1, one RAG is there.
PAUL: In IV schools, we have worked on that fidget, because we know what was the curriculum, we had the books, the PDFs based on that, we have done it.
PAUL: Okay. But yes, please let me know your solution.
Rahul Parihar: This is really good, guys, you know, thanks, Paul, for… this was… this class was really exciting.
PAUL: We are with time. Don't, worry. I will come to you. Yes, next, everybody I have unmuted.
PAUL: It's 12.21 only, so I know I have a lot of time for the discussion. TSO Youth, or anybody else, they want to go.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, it hit…
PAUL: if…
Rohit Srivastava: Hey, Paul, I don't know why I'm getting an echo.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright, don't worry, I'll continue. So, the fast mode of operation
Rohit Srivastava: That preset is equal to fast.
Rohit Srivastava: For some reason, it's not working for me.
Rohit Srivastava: I can share with you my screen.
PAUL: Alright, alright.
PAUL: Alright, Mohanadi, you're telling Ape did not understand in the first 4 sessions.
PAUL: alright? You can let me know exactly the part where you are having the problems, I can always have a discussion.
PAUL: Okay, I'm on it.
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, can you see my screen?
PAUL: Okay, if not, then probably I will ask someone.
PAUL: Yes, I can see, I can look into the video.
Rohit Srivastava: if I'm executing this, It just gives me…
Rohit Srivastava: Because it's not loading anything into the documents.
Rohit Srivastava: Alright, now, if I change it to balanced.
PAUL: Oh, Pokemon.
PAUL: See, balanced all right.
Rohit Srivastava: And then, see?
Rohit Srivastava: It just works.
PAUL: Okay, so very specifically with respect to the preset change that is.
PAUL: Always applying the pixet look into that document variable, whether something is there or not. If there only anything.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay.
PAUL: When you actually activate that load, like, load or parse.
PAUL: data, so that particular variable is your documents. Please focus on that one.
Rohit Srivastava: Try to print it out.
PAUL: Yes, just wait.
Rohit Srivastava: No, no, documents is… when we choose the preset is equal to false, dog, Dr.
PAUL: bring cloud.var variable.
PAUL: That's why. Please print out the document variable and show me the output.
PAUL: From there, you will understand, because if it is showing your list index out of range, it means that, probably, within the document, it could not fetch anything.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, so, so…
PAUL: generally, like, Within that print, again, no space, no space.
digvijay reddy: Yeah, even I'm facing a document out-of-range error. I tried to rectify it, but it's saying document not available.
PAUL: Yes, directly it will say, if for a specific mode it happens, I have seen that.
digvijay reddy: Yeah.
PAUL: Sometimes changing the result type helps.
digvijay reddy: Yeah, the same error I made is index out of range, and I'm not sure why, Paul.
PAUL: Yeah, because…
Rohit Srivastava: Preset physical force is not loading it.
PAUL: Reset is equal to fast, I think, no?
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, preset is first.
digvijay reddy: Correct. Yeah.
PAUL: Yes. Change it to, balanced, it is working. Premium also is working? Yes.
PAUL: Yeah, only fast is not working.
PAUL: Change the result type to text lengthy for fast.
PAUL: In the past, I have seen…
Rohit Srivastava: lost.
PAUL: Upon rendering, it happened. Change the result type to text.
Rohit Srivastava: Next.
PAUL: Now run it.
Rohit Srivastava: Let's see…
PAUL: Because in markdown rendering, it happens sometimes in fast mode. It's… With respect to tech…
Rohit Srivastava: Yeah, exactly.
digvijay reddy: David?
PAUL: Okay.
Rohit Srivastava: books.
PAUL: The issue was coming, because you were rendering in that markdown.
PAUL: I'm back.
PAUL: too fast and markdown, because of that, there was some type of parsing issue.
Rohit Srivastava: Okay, thank you.
PAUL: Always for everyone, please do check out with the result type, rather than changing premium, because I know with respect to exporting in markdown or text, there can be issue.
Rohit Srivastava: Thanks, Sorangshu, and have a great day. I'll take a leave.
PAUL: Alright, we will hit next.
PAUL: Next, next. So many people I've unmuted.
PAUL: Nitesh, Digvijay… Yes, Modasa, Jeninka…
digvijay reddy: My error was the same one as previous call. Thanks a lot.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, the equation is done.
PAUL: Next.
Jainika: Look at me? Mino?
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, please, for it.
Jainika: Yes, Paul, I just want to thank you first, and I just want some guidance.
Jainika: Actually, I have 10 years of experience in Java J2E, in server-side applications, wherein I were using… working on Kubernetes and Kafka CICD pipelines. So, I just want, my transition to learn this, this.
Jainika: RAG applications working onto the Gen AI. So, what all other things I need to understand, as my experience is quite high, so…
PAUL: Based on your experience, first of all, I feel that, okay, like, Kafka, surface site environments, okay, you only need to focus on this Pythonic frameworks, okay, and the actual tech content.
PAUL: Because your experience is also right, so probably you need to, like, provide an entire solution, designing solutions. These are the things, sites that you'll be working a lot, like handling a team. You won't be an individual.
PAUL: contributed so much. So, like, when you are managing a team, with respect to decision making, I feel that few things with respect to ML design systems that you can focus on.
PAUL: Because that's good, like, you have worked already with Kafka and others, so really, that part is really important.
PAUL: Because most of the times, we work with huge amount of data. So, but with respect to technical stuff much more, like the LLM side.
PAUL: rag side we are discussing in this course, by… I know that after 2 to 3 months, LLM in good, place. But that LLM part is important. You need to explore that thing.
PAUL: Okay, yeah.
Jainika: So, do I need to do that course, which is starting in Jan? So, actually, I don't know much.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. That course is not. You are already having 10 years of experience. That course, useless. You will spend 6 months.
PAUL: Because Python basics, you are already coming from Java background. Java to Python, it's easy. For Python to Java, it is very hard.
PAUL: Okay, so in your case, that course won't help you, and there is still now not a single course which has been launched where we deal with LLM stuff only.
PAUL: It's much more consuming elements, because really, if I try to teach you training and other stuff, I might be spending $3,000, and every people will just watch and see.
PAUL: Because you need to spend a lot to learn that particular thing. In your organization, you can do it, because you will be having cloud access, and you can explore those things.
PAUL: Most of my other students who have questions, I always share them. I will share one piece of code, but that piece of code might take time. So, in your case, I will say that, yes, fine-tuning elements, very important, quantization.
PAUL: or parallelms. Few topics are there that you need to explore from your end.
Jainika: Actually, in my organization, such work is not, done. So, can you suggest any course or something like that?
PAUL: There is no such person who teaches you. There are a few people who have some blogs. You can drop me a mail, I can share with you.
PAUL: Okay, probably for that also, because till now, I can say, in the market, very few people, it means that if I'm showing you in production, actually, how fine-tuning is done, that is… nobody has shown, I feel that. In a few books only, it is written.
PAUL: Okay, and there is one good book, Building a… LLM from scratch.
PAUL: At least, please go through that, okay? That book will help you a lot to grab the fundamental concepts.
Jainika: Okay.
Jainika: Thank you.
PAUL: Okay, that, because, only two people are directly telling you. One is, I think, Andrej Kaparti is there. He has some videos directly, working from scratch LLMs, and the other one is Sebastian Rashfa.
PAUL: Only two people are there, so they have the major content, and few people are there in Substack that I know. I'm subscribed, so if you want those, let me know, I will share you those resources.
PAUL: Alright, next.
PAUL: Yes, anybody can go ahead.
PAUL: Okay, Suwash, Nitesh, Janika, so many people I have unmuted, so…
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, well, so, I mean, thanks overall, the session is good and all, trying to make the most of things.
Mudassar Hakim: Although I do feel somehow the sessions, I mean, the entire module here is something…
Mudassar Hakim: Maybe I'm not fit for it right now, I'm just trying to salvage what I can.
PAUL: See, these modules, nobody learns, really. If I was there, I will never teach, but
PAUL: directly, if I start using Doclink, some people might say, really? Like, frameworks, nobody needs to run. If you are a developer, you always go through the documentation, okay?
Mudassar Hakim: today.
PAUL: Go to the doctor, that's the biggest occupied.
Mudassar Hakim: here is the thing, right? I mean, obviously, even I have around 17 years experience now. I'm driving projects, but at the end of the day, I have exposure to Java, Go, Rust, even React and Node, all those things. But now, if I have to drive projects
Mudassar Hakim: with this technical stack, I have not done much development.
Mudassar Hakim: I can definitely rely on tools, like Claude and other things, where they can tell me what can be done better. But.
PAUL: Like, for example, if I'm discussing a tech stack, if you want to switch now, what will be your tech stack? You can let me know. In Rust, a lot of things are available, you can do it in Rust.
PAUL: But in… till now, like, in other programming languages, I won't say there is so much support.
Mudassar Hakim: Right. But boiling here, it's more of a general history. What I'm trying to say is that these are the languages which I have handled projects in, and now this is the area which I want to get into and capitalize. Now.
Mudassar Hakim: I think the delta here is that I'm obviously not at a developer level, so I'm not able to get to do a lot of hands-on. Although, if I try to squeeze out time and deprioritize things which are at work, I might get to do it, but I think so that is not happening. So… I don't know, if there is a certain…
Mudassar Hakim: different approach I should be taking, or this is a different course maybe you guys are willing to create. I also…
PAUL: about which.
Mudassar Hakim: Oh, funny.
PAUL: of a work.
Mudassar Hakim: With respect to leaders who are responsible for driving projects.
PAUL: I think for that, there's that AI…
PAUL: I think AI Leaders Batch is there, I think Mank is taking that one.
PAUL: AI for leaders, something like that.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay…
PAUL: It's at night, I think, from 8 or 9, because my bank handles that one. I know. AI for Leaders, it has been launched around November, or before Ragged that batch was.
Mudassar Hakim: I don't see that, right now in your…
PAUL: But that is less technical. It means that less development. It's much more new-code stuff at every point of time.
Mudassar Hakim: Exactly, exactly. And that's the problem, right, Paul? No-code is… I mean, it's a… it's a shapeshift, you know, a kind of a bootleg thing kind of doing things, to be very honest. If I really take things to production, no-code is just gonna…
Mudassar Hakim: I know, this is my perspective, you can correct me if I'm wrong. No code can sustain to a certain extent, but beyond that, we need that, granular configuration, customization, where every client
Mudassar Hakim: For their…
PAUL: Basically, that for a small service, you can use it, but your product cannot be based totally on Moko.
Mudassar Hakim: Exactly.
PAUL: It can be a small service.
Mudassar Hakim: Exactly. So, I think so we're on the same page here. So that's where I'm coming from, that when we have to scale a certain division on a certain product with respect to using what we can get from RAG, from LLMs, from fine-tuning, from evaluation, and create a deliverable, because, see, I get the part when you say, right, this is all
Mudassar Hakim: SDLC stuff, DevOps stuff. But at the end of the day, the business today, the environment is such that they are okay to see a POC, but they are not willing to invest if they don't see the entire picture, end-to-end, right?
PAUL: In that picture, if you need, really, an investment from it. You have to just focus on two things, time and energy. Somehow. Like, how impacting… your solution is impacting how much time and how much early.
PAUL: This, if I am looking, because majorly for AI products, with respect to in, like, the venture capitalists around the world.
PAUL: Okay, everybody is ready to spend on AI.
Mudassar Hakim: But actually, like, how much they will earn.
PAUL: Simply, if it's at least 4x to 5X, then they will think. If I'm talking about major GSB ventures, major, like, Capital, Sikawa, because I know that growth, okay? It's a very small lobby, and, like, in India, really less people are interested. In US, they are pouring a lot of money.
PAUL: Okay, that's for it. Because,
PAUL: most of the Indian solutions, they are good, but defining only two things, time and revenue, where it fails.
PAUL: It reminded me of winter sometimes.
Mudassar Hakim: But that's where folks like us step in, right, Paul? Where we will have to call out and justify the efforts balancing the revenue. A very simple use case today, we are talking about parsers.
Mudassar Hakim: Right? Right from the basic docklings to the advanced and paying Llama Index, or Llama parser that we saw. At the end of the day, they will be relying on us to tell them what to do.
Mudassar Hakim: And that is only possible if I have that depth understanding, you know, customization point of view, what works, to what's… what… on the basis of what…
PAUL: I got your point. It means that some type of USP that you were defining for the particular product based on something.
Mudassar Hakim: Go to that level and propose at that level, maybe this is more of a consulting, maybe, I think so, where this is driving it. But even when I have to consult, right, my bare bones are still my technicals. I know the technicals, that's why I'm able to forecast and estimate and talk at a broader level. So…
Mudassar Hakim: I don't know, I'm just thinking here, out loud, that if there is a customization that I need to look in terms of my preparation, or a different program altogether, I need to get into, I mean, I'm just very openly and candidly asking you, if you are aware, that is.
PAUL: Rico.
Mudassar Hakim: deviate, I'll be more than happy to pivot here.
PAUL: because with respect to designs and other things, that is discussed much more. But there, nothing, it is technical. It means that directly, probably using anything, okay, those type of tools, it's… okay, and probably if…
PAUL: I don't think, because in that syllabus, there's… it's like integration with Tableau, reporting, dashboard, those type of stuff is there much more.
PAUL: Okay, so you can have a look into that, at least. Go through the syllabus, whatever's proposed, because even… I have not created the curriculum, but I have…
Mudassar Hakim: The leadership thing,
PAUL: Yes, AI for Leaders, I think so.
Mudassar Hakim: I don't see it in the live classes, URL. I'm looking at it right now. I can see Ultimate Rag, GenAI for everyone,
PAUL: Oh, sweet.
Mudassar Hakim: You don't need to have the access, no.
PAUL: Generally, no, no, no, no.
PAUL: Okay, you could just read.
PAUL: Gosh, my… This one, I think, is also available.
PAUL: Yes, this is the one, okay. Let me see if I can…
Mudassar Hakim: They're on the live page, actually.
PAUL: No, no, no, you won't get the access. Even there is not a PDF…
PAUL: And that I can share with you.
PAUL: But this is one I know, okay, probably. If you want to drop me a mail, I will share the details by tagging the team in the mail.
Nitesh: I can pitch in here, because I am part of that session as well, the AI for Leadership Professionals.
PAUL: Nitesh, then great student to student.
Nitesh: Yeah, right, so… I'm sorry, I'm not sure whom I'm talking to.
Mudassar Hakim: What does that, Nipesh.
Nitesh: Yeah, Melissa, yep. Melissa, basically, that course is, like, getting the introduction to the AI, understanding the low-code tool, and probably having integration with your general workflows with…
Nitesh: using NATN and understand how the APIs work and everything. So, it's, like, more to… for anybody who's getting into the AI, understanding the elements, understanding…
Mudassar Hakim: of this.
Nitesh: Different tools.
Mudassar Hakim: Thanks, Nitesh, for highlighting that.
Nitesh: A little bit of film.
Mudassar Hakim: So that's what the mismatch is, Paul. Today, I know how to use NATain, I can go and deploy my self-forcing server and run the NATN also over there. At least I have that capability. So that's where I realized there, you know, these generic or introductory sessions, you know, for leadership. That's not something that will… thanks, Nitesh, for pitching in. But nevertheless, Nitesh, can you just try sharing
Mudassar Hakim: the PDF, maybe I'll just try to extract something which is meaningful to me.
Mudassar Hakim: I'll share my email address, I don't know if I can share it, I think I'm only available to host and panelists. I'll share it in our group.
Mudassar Hakim: messages. I'll share my email over there. But Paul, this is just a seed, thought, which I'm sharing with you, that this is a common problem statement for people who are plus 15 years, who are into leadership today. That they are trying to figure out that playbook
Mudassar Hakim: That tomorrow, if projects have to be designed, have to be selected, have to be estimated, forecast, balancing cost versus,
Mudassar Hakim: real-time application, right? That kind of template today, it's missing in the market, and I'm trying my best to go through various courses, whether it's through Triple ID Bangalore programs, Krishnaik programs, which I'm going through right now, and even the smallest one. That piece is not there in the market. And if there is something, I'll be more than happy to go through it and…
PAUL: A few people asked, so similarly, your requirement is here, is actually a set-up thing, okay, which is used by very less people.
PAUL: It means that if somebody creates a course.
PAUL: Do you think that… how many weeks will come? It's only for leaders' weeks, if somebody is there.
Mudassar Hakim: tell you there's a huge market, Paul. I can tell you. Right now, we don't know it because the.
PAUL: We have already tried.
Mudassar Hakim: We have already… we already do our marketing, we spend a lot, so I'm telling you.
PAUL: A rough estimation, generally, like, when we say very specifically, this batch is specialized for people, like, more than 10 years, if I'm taking.
PAUL: We already received, like, less number of students who'll be there, close to less than 100 also.
PAUL: Sometimes we might reach close to 200, 250 by telling that if this is for beginners. The requirement of this, generally what happens in our case, a simple mathematics. If we are pricing less, then ideas, at least we should have lesser, or more number of students.
PAUL: But in that case, that our formula of less pricing breaks.
Mudassar Hakim: Exactly.
PAUL: That's the way.
Mudassar Hakim: And that's where I was coming in. I am, as a professional today, who gets to know that I'm getting the relevant content, specific to my requirements, I am brave to bump up another zero or another two zeros on that number.
PAUL: Without being good.
Mudassar Hakim: report this session. And I'm sure other professionals on my level.
PAUL: people.
Mudassar Hakim: More than happy to do it, considering that getting their money's worth.
PAUL: I got your point, see. I have worked in techs a lot, so I know that in India, it is not possible.
PAUL: In India, not… if you're in English?
Mudassar Hakim: That's pretty okay. I mean, Paul, that's why I'm stressing this again and again. If you have an exposure where outside India also, we have something structured and relevant, maybe someone from your peer circle that might know, I'll be.
PAUL: Back in, like, 2023, we have already tested in the US market, probably, like, with $2,000. Okay, we got enrollments, like, close to 50.
PAUL: But, actually, that's the thing, see, when we are devoting time, we all don't think about only treating 15.
PAUL: That becomes… We prefer rather than, let's take much more.
PAUL: Because for 15 people, I want to spend such a time.
PAUL: Rather than, why not handle more people?
PAUL: That is the main thing. See, going forward, probably next year, because, see, right now, the team is very small, only 3 to 4 people, so I cannot ask anybody to do that. But, going forward, probably next year, because I have a plan only to make a course for LGX.
PAUL: no RAG stuff or another, because RAG is the first experiment that I'm doing. My second experiment will be LLM-based only.
PAUL: pure elements. But I know, yes, few people will only be coming, but I told, fine, I will take the risk.
PAUL: It means that, the mentor need to tell the risk of somebody. If I say that, okay, I will do the launch, that's the main pain point.
PAUL: And marketing is an important component. Like, in our case, I know everybody's looking for niche content.
PAUL: Something close to production. Now, really, to teach close to production, it's really hard.
PAUL: It means that if something comes with experience, people who are not having experience, it becomes a problem.
Mudassar Hakim: So, due to mixed crowd, we always try to remove a lot of things.
PAUL: That might not be relevant for everyone.
PAUL: Okay, but this time, little bit different, like, few people are there, which I feel like who can contribute in this course. For them, few advanced functionalities which are not part of this course, but with respect to development that I can take contribute.
PAUL: So that's why some open source stuff that I will start in this batch, probably after 45 days, once people are comfortable with the project.
Mudassar Hakim: No, no, Paul, this has been an excellent course. If I had been taking this, like, 10, 15, 12 years.
PAUL: I got your point. As a developer point of view.
Mudassar Hakim: Today, if I have to, you know, get into the seat of decision-making, I understand. I know technical stuff, so even for that also, decision-making, it's all t-shirt size. Numbers fluctuate by a good 20-30%. There's always a spillover. Even for any other, you know, full-stack applications that we do on production.
Mudassar Hakim: So I expect the same happening for LLM-based or rack-based applications also. But that template is missing in the market today. Today, if I have to do this for a back-end project, front-end project, there's a lot of…
Mudassar Hakim: Evaluating criterias I know already, what I need to go through to take a decision.
Mudassar Hakim: But for such things, it's very open-ended, very, very open-ended. Just like the example I took, right? The parsing thing, very open-ended. Something can work, something doesn't work. So it's all risk.
Mudassar Hakim: And, to be very honest, you know what risk is all about. The way you spoke about launching, right? Same thing happens to us. When I take a decision in ownership to drive something, it's my neck on the line. That you took the decision, or you drive it. All the numbers…
Mudassar Hakim: profit and loss, you know, work we call as P&L. That is something, now it's your headache. You take care. That's how leadership works.
PAUL: on your point.
Mudassar Hakim: Not to take more time here, but just laying a thought, Paul, where I'm coming from, and I'm trying my best to salvage whatever I can from this course, and I'm sure it will benefit me. I'll try to…
PAUL: Actually, like, probably next year, I'll be taking, like, only a few people. And, like, probably from other batches also. The idea is to only take people from more than 10 years of experience.
PAUL: And where is the bottleneck that you are feeling? Let's try to cover those, because once that consolidated report we have from different batches, then actually we can think about it.
PAUL: Okay, I think in that way it will be good. Exact…
PAUL: Or somewhere close to specific requirements.
Mudassar Hakim: Sure, sure. But as I said, Paul, if you see something, hear something regarding where I'm coming from, you know, please be, be very candidly, you know, letting me know. I'll be more than happy to try it out.
PAUL: Perfect, for sure.
Mudassar Hakim: Awesome. Thanks, boy.
PAUL: Next…
Nitesh: Amen.
PAUL: Anybody can go ahead. Yes.
Nitesh: I was waiting for that. So, Paul, I think I… actually, I missed the last two classes, basically. So, I'm just trying to clear my understanding. So, what I understood is, like, when we started with the Langchain, we discussed about the document lot of.
PAUL: data growth.
PAUL: Yeah.
Nitesh: data loaders. So, it is a.
PAUL: It's the thing that we are…
Nitesh: Yeah.
PAUL: Yes. Now, going forward, what happens? You might see that, okay, for your kind of documents, very specifically, like, one of the features from doctoring is working really good.
PAUL: Now, the idea is that, okay, now similarly, one of the things for mount structure. So, generally, in your data ingestion pipeline, you have that hybrid. It means that it can be a mixture of dockling, it can be a mixture of mount structure. Lang channel is fine. Same stuff, reading. At the end of the deal, it's only about reading files and getting the data.
PAUL: So, if you have missed anything, there is no problem, because in this particular project, when I don't remember exactly, so the parsing, I think I might have done it directly through land chin only. So, not a problem.
Nitesh: Okay, okay, so just, like, exploring the different options are available, and probably having the understanding that what works best with the use case.
PAUL: Yeah.
Nitesh: Something like that.
PAUL: a little bit of experimentation is required, just to understand that, okay, for your type of documents, is, like, this is working good or this is… generally, like, Langchain data loaders, we don't use it. We use a proper framework, like DogLinks, Unstructured, okay, all LlamaPass, that is that.
Nitesh: Okay, okay. Then my follow-up question I have is that I missed to understand that when you're using this Lama parsing over a cloud and asking us to get the API, so does it mean that every parsing I'm using that is going to a cloud.
PAUL: Only the API key for LAMA service.
PAUL: If you want to use some external, vendor, okay, then you need to pass it.
PAUL: One is to connect the service, to do the authentication.
PAUL: Okay, now if you use some premium type of service, probably more credits will be used.
PAUL: Okay, so you have to really understand, if you're bringing some external LLM into the picture, then you need to pass the API key for that certain service.
PAUL: Otherwise, it.
Nitesh: Yeah, then I understood. Yeah, then I understood. So, my question was, actually, when we are using this Lama pass, and there's a, like, the passing with LLMs, or passing with VLM, possibly, then I think when we are using those packages, probably, then it will hit the API.
PAUL: Yes, yes. If you try to define there, your customers are probably going to switch to GPT. In those cases, yes, you need to bring your API.
Nitesh: Otherwise, the libraries which we are using, it's like local API, locally passing the document, okay.
PAUL: It's in-server, not local.
PAUL: Nothing is there in local.
Nitesh: Oh, I wouldn'.
PAUL: I'm mute.
Nitesh: importing the libraries and the packages, right? It is in my virtual environment, and those.
PAUL: Okay, those are a few, yes, the Llama main core packages. But actually, you do always an authentication. It means that the amount of the processing that you are doing, yes, it is in local, but a copy that always goes into the cloud.
PAUL: Who would be.
Nitesh: Oh.
PAUL: You are exposing your data.
Nitesh: Ramos.
PAUL: Llama Cloud, yes. It means that you are sending your information there. It's not entirely local. That is the thing I want to say.
Nitesh: Okay, then in that case, for my enterprise solutions, possibly, this would…
Nitesh: I won't be able to do.
PAUL: Yes, he'.
Nitesh: Good evening.
PAUL: they might reject it. In that case, you need to look for docklings and unstructured-based solutions.
Nitesh: Oh, okay, this helps. Thanks, thanks, Zumba.
PAUL: Alright, Nitesh, next.
Suyash: Hello, good afternoon, sir. Good afternoon.
PAUL: Yes.
Suyash: Absolutely.
PAUL: Excuse me.
Suyash: Yeah, thank you so much for the course. I mean, I was thinking I will not get a chance today, but somehow I am. I'm not sure how, but I got…
Suyash: Thank you for that. So, my question will be related to… I mean, two questions I asked. Firstly, related to carriers, because I was thinking from a lot of time I wanted to ask this question. So, sir, my, like, experience is around 7 years, okay? And I'm currently… I mean, I've worked, until now.
Suyash: As a, I mean, data analyst, using Alteryx, Power BI, PowerTheX, and also in the data engineering side, building data warehousing.
Suyash: I have done, like, a year, I mean, some offline course in Delhi related to this, machine learning and all, and now I was doing this. But I, like, the problem is, like, I am not sure, like, how I will…
Suyash: I mean, get opportunity to transition into exactly this, because I was asking for some kind of project internally, but, like, they were not having exactly, so…
Suyash: this stuff.
PAUL: So, exactly, like, what you were looking for, that part I want.
Suyash: na machine learner.
PAUL: See, it's… I got your point, like, you were looking for a switch.
PAUL: But before that switch, like, exactly what type of work, like, development-related company or your coach, or…
Suyash: Certainly, I mean, purely development, hardware reports, Alteryx, Workflow, create kernel, SQL, Data Warehousing, Joby, Python, maybe, data cleansing, EDA, those kind of.
PAUL: Okay, all right. Much more towards aligning towards data analyst type of tasks that you have already done.
PAUL: Data engineering analog. Engineering means, have you worked with pipelines, worked with Kafka, Kynasik, these type of streaming?
PAUL: little bit of big data that comes. But I got your point. Generally, from data analyst to data science, it's easier to switch. It's not very hard. It means that some fundamental level that you have, but actually, like, what type of role are you directly looking for Gen AI-based role?
PAUL: then it can be a problem. It means that if you're looking for some type of machine learning-based tools, okay, or at least deep learning, because the idea is that you need to have that fundamental understanding. You can look for GenA also, but
PAUL: If you have zero experience in the data field, it becomes a problem. You can see that I have that data analyst who, yes, I can.
Suyash: Finally.
PAUL: Think that you can make a switch. It totally depends upon the JD definition, but experience with cloud has to be very good. Whichever cloud that you have been working, one cloud, just be very, very good in that.
Suyash: So, sir, which exactly niche I need to pick? Like, I was currently, as I was doing this course, I was thinking to go into this agentic AI, or, like, just.
PAUL: Don't bear before moving to Agent KIT, you have the foundations of machine learning.
PAUL: And deep learning. That is the main thing. If you don't have… it's a bad practice, directly jump to… Jenny, if you're getting the role, take it. Later on, you can do the learning. But if you feel that, based on the learning, somebody will give you the job.
PAUL: Because if somebody asks to me, I can ask very simple questions with respect to LLM, which are based on deep learning. There is nothing GenAI.
PAUL: That's fine, like, HS for basic utah, like, once you.
PAUL: covered at least. Once you get the job, then forget. Doesn't matter, but…
PAUL: Those type of positions, it is required.
PAUL: Because a lot of the basics going forward, decision-making is very hard. Like, to do this, which should I do, what type of model should I take into, okay, how can I make my data better into this experiences are the other.
PAUL: da-da-da.
PAUL: So, just share me a resume I have to look into, because a lot of things with respect to data analysts, that few things that might you need to review.
PAUL: Okay, so please do share me your latest resume, and based on that, I will let you.
Suyash: Sure, sure, thank you so much.
PAUL: Next.
Amit Singh: Paul, sir, can I go next?
PAUL: Huh, I'm gonna see people.
Amit Singh: Hi. So, thank you so much, yeah, I mean, you know, I mean, echoing what Rahul Parir said, what Modestar said, I mean, definitely glad, you know, I'm attending an international-level stuff.
Amit Singh: I had, like, throw…
Amit Singh: seeing the tone of the discussions that has been going on, I also… like, I have 20 years of experience, so one component I want to understand, if you can…
Amit Singh: counsel me as well as to how to shape up the career, because after working at SAP and a lot of MNCs, I mean.
Amit Singh: I came with a technical solution and selling background, right? For 15 odd years, and then I had… for the last 7 years, I had a lot of career breaks. I mean, I was teaching also, you know. Teaching as in… I mean, I did a PG program, and I taught
Amit Singh: After that, there was a career gap of 2 years again, in which I learned, machine learning and data science. Because in 2016, I was trying to learn, and it was not fitting in very well. Online, I… from Courtsera.
PAUL: In 2016, I feel.
Amit Singh: Yo.
PAUL: At that time, there was a single course from Andrew NG in Coursera. After that, a lot of things has evolved, because even I started back in 2016.
Amit Singh: So, I mean, I came out of SAP, the world was very different, you know, and I mean, from the open source side. So, SaaS was there, they said, you come to Bombay, then we have the center over there only, and then we'll teach you for 9 months. I wanted to get into data analytics, I mean, to cut short.
Amit Singh: But somehow I, I mean, I tried registering at ISC Bangalore for that data analytics program, but somehow I landed at IIT Rootkey since that price was less, but again, this was more on the coding side.
Amit Singh: But I stuck with it, you know? So my theory is very strong, you know, in terms of machine learning, NLP, or even if it is not strong, I can understand what is happening, you know? Like, even if I'm lagging in your classes, but when I sit with the notebook and the video again throughout the week.
Amit Singh: I'm able to understand, I'm able to catch up at least, and I can tell what is happening. You know, at least what you are teaching? Or…
PAUL: Utai, like, I can understand it.
Amit Singh: I'm unable to… unable to keep pace.
PAUL: So, it happens, like, take another goat cheese pudaja, you can actually take it very quick. But the things, if something is new, so that's pretty much common. We also know that among our students, metabolism rate Alla Gutta.
PAUL: So, really, we can understand that.
Amit Singh: Yeah, so one is that, I mean, I also want… I'll share a mail, I send my resume also, if you can guide me. You know, I mean, I was working as a technical project manager, I mean, I made the switch, you know, I was studying in the last… with the last faculty.
Amit Singh: there I got a break, and I worked with McKisson, which is into… it's one of the largest healthcare, and they had an oncology team, and I was working on that ETL pipeline, creating drug combinations for cancer research patients, you know.
Amit Singh: So, there I was handling engineers and a BA, right? And, on the UI also, I mean, they wanted to develop a visualization also, so I handled two projects, approximately.
Amit Singh: But what Mudarsha was echoing, no? I mean, at this stage.
Amit Singh: I mean, that is what I decided, you know, I mean, what he was echoing, basically, that I should know coding.
Amit Singh: If I'm shipping the code, you know, from dev to UAT to QC to prod, right, I should understand what is happening and what features I'm building, right? Because I was owning the project.
Amit Singh: the requirement.
PAUL: Oh, great.
Amit Singh: coming from their side only. I mean, it varies from company to company and project to project, you know.
PAUL: Good.
Amit Singh: industrialization.
PAUL: It's like, get, get.
Amit Singh: So, so… there's definitely a space what Mudhasar is echoing, right? But I.
PAUL: I know.
Amit Singh: that I should understand coding, and that is why, you know, I again challenged myself when I was speaking to Krishtha that day, that Ikbar firseh karte, code, you know, I mean, weak in Python.
Amit Singh: So, my challenge is that, you know, should I work as a TPM? Should I work as a business analyst? As a GenAI developer, wokol aata hai, shortlist hota hai resume lekin, you know, under se gut feel nahi ati ke me code kar panga, because una practice nih, I have not developed any model on my own, yet.
Amit Singh: I can sit and read books, I have that kind of patience, or if I do coding, I take a lot of time, you know? A lot of time as in, like, I can spend a half a day just trying to build that thing.
Amit Singh: So I'm more strong on the research part, you know, I mean, that…
Amit Singh: VLNM Padliya, VLM Padliya, kyahay, GitHub uska Deklya. I understand solution architectures also very well, because that is what I was doing for the last 15 years, right? What component is.
PAUL: That's the main thing that…
Amit Singh: From where the data is going. Okay. It is talking like this, and this is not what we are doing, and I can go back to the client and…
Amit Singh: basis the business requirement, I can tell… take a call, and if I have good technical knowledge, what the discussion earlier was happening, then I can really fit into that component, you know, that I know. So.
Amit Singh: I can search the market as to what is the best, you know, and then pick and choose the component, evaluating those risk analysis, you know, what technicality, what can fit in, what not.
Amit Singh: So, I want to reach that level, so… but ab is industry mein concept role may kam karna hai is me confuse waram, because jo, role RA mo development ki RA, and that is what I'm not. So, you know, basically, I'm stuck in my career.
PAUL: Deployment don't pick up dev roles, much more architect-based roles, principal engineer, ESR roles, I think.
PAUL: That is much more fit, because…
PAUL: Rather than a component part, as you said, you will be working on that full, like, some… I can say, little bit of technical, little bit of business side. Correct. Both that you will be taking care of. In that case, it's much more architecting stuff, I feel.
PAUL: Designing their context.
Amit Singh: I mean…
Amit Singh: It so happens that, I mean, I don't want to fake myself, right? I've not worked as a solution architect, I don't have that tag. I just have a project manager tag, or you can call me a technical project manager, so-called. But I had a parallel who was more sound, and I was relying on his intelligence, you know? And I was driving him, and I was trying to research that he's not making mistakes.
Amit Singh: And together, we were delivering the project, and it went very well, because he was technically very sound, and…
Amit Singh: We took care of the complexities.
Amit Singh: We definitely took care of the complexities.
Amit Singh: So…
PAUL: You know the theoretical part well, okay, and if you can handle teams, okay, focus on, like.
PAUL: Solutions part, much more. Matlog designs.
PAUL: ML system design, okay, a few things that comes there very specifically focus much more on those things.
Amit Singh: But we don't get a role for ML system design only, you know? I mean, it is more for what, like.
PAUL: That rule is for if you are looking for anything architect, anyone more than 10 years of experience for them, I can say. It is very, very important. Because when you actually go there for an interview, okay, it really doesn't matter. They will majorly focus on the system design. They will give you a problem statement, and they will say that Mujapura Design Kargetika.
PAUL: In any big companies I have seen.
PAUL: We're starting, say, like, a data kahasar, and finally how the client is getting poore Joe Fluent data. That part you need to explain. So, for that, I feel you need to focus on design systems much more.
PAUL: And where I can…
Amit Singh: where I can study this, or what websites do I.
PAUL: Design systems, few people are there, and very niche.
Amit Singh: ByteByte Go is there, ByteByte Go is there, system designs… I mean, on Substack, I have, subscribed to that, and I keep getting those notifications.
PAUL: Bite, Bite Go is fine, but one book is there by Chef Rohan. Okay, that is, I think, email system design or something like that. That book was very, very famous back in 20…
PAUL: I think 3.
Amit Singh: Chip, you in again. I subscribed her on this one, I'll buy that book, which you recommended.
PAUL: The cheap one has two main books. One is that AI Engineering, that is really good for gen AI engineers. For Gen AI engineers, that is just, like, a Bible to start that, I feel. And the other one comes for experienced guys only, which is that ML system design.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay. This came… this came earlier, huh?
PAUL: Yes, first, machine learning came, then AI engineering came.
Amit Singh: Okay, Alex, who also has ML System Design book? I have one, like, I… I bought from…
PAUL: Still going, I have done that one, like, 3 years back, I was going through, and it is really good.
PAUL: caught you. Because few people are there, only I feel that very, very few people are there who have actually done that.
Amit Singh: I'll try searching this, I'll… Anyways, I'll be sharing my resume with you, just do guide me.
Amit Singh: like, I've got a call from Turing as of now, for lead business analyst, but, so what they can ask, I mean, technical rounds, will they be asking Python, or, like.
PAUL: every, like, Python can be in the stack. For business intelligence.
PAUL: type of rules, it will be much more, like, once the data is there, yes, for VA, like, I feel that VA guys work a lot with data warehousing solutions, okay? From there, you fetch the data, you'll be creating your reports, and probably publish it to Tableau, ClickView, these type of tools, much more.
Amit Singh: No, this side I have not explored much, because my entire.
PAUL: That is important, because for BIPS rules, that is a cool thing. You'll be working with data warehousing solutions a lot. From there, you will fetch the data, and then you will be creating reports, and you'll be automating the stuff.
Amit Singh: what, like, Suyash was asking, I didn't take that path. Somehow, like, you know, I've taken the engineering path, I mean, I started, I mean, basic ML, then the Gen AI part, you know, so I did everything that was there in the… I studied this one, I mean.
Amit Singh: Orlyn Geron, I studied that. So, that book I have studied.
Amit Singh: I mean, that is what they were following at IIT Rudki, to teach.
Amit Singh: Oh…
PAUL: Oral lean?
Amit Singh: Get on.
PAUL: Okay, hands-on, hands-on.
Amit Singh: Hands on, yeah, yeah.
PAUL: I got it, got it, I got it. I read that book back in 2021, I think.
PAUL: It's good. It's for, like, machine learning engineers and deep learning engineers. That's a very good book.
Amit Singh: Yeah, so I studied from that. The basics are from that, so…
PAUL: But in business intelligence, you will be working with data warehousing solutions, and… because the idea is that, okay, once the data engineering team pulls the data there, okay, now it's the job of BI guys, actually, to perform your queries on top of that. So, some type of data warehousing
PAUL: I think Redshift and Amazon, which is widely used in my organization. So, I know the BA guys do that.
PAUL: Perfume, perfume.
Amit Singh: Okay, coming to the setup part, what you were teaching, if I can quickly share my screen.
PAUL: Just wait.
PAUL: One is that.
Amit Singh: Yeah, this.
PAUL: Okay, Shushantha, Naga, a few people have done Arvani, Bhagwanda, everyone I have one unmuted.
PAUL: You can start sharing. Amit, in the meantime, who wants to montage? First, you…
Amit Singh: this.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: We want to…
PAUL: montage.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay. Mantage aloud there.
PAUL: Okay, then, Armani, I think you can go ahead.
Amit Singh: My… this pip install requirement has been… I'll just take 2 more minutes.
PAUL: Okay, fine. I'm looking into your screen only. Yes, I can see, okay, the installations are going, InfoCape is still looking at multiple versions of Llama Index CLI to determine this could take a while. Now, it will look for every possible version which will get supported in your system. This part takes time.
PAUL: Nothing that we can do. I think it will try to install different versions of that Llama Index CLI package.
Amit Singh: Okay, okay, okay. And project I have not created in, Langsmith yet, so we'll do it tomorrow?
PAUL: Langs, let me just be sure you have that API keys. REST, tomorrow, we will start everything from scratch only.
Amit Singh: API key I have configured.
PAUL: That's the only thing, because tomorrow I will create a blank folder, within that blank folder, what are the things that are important. Step by step, we will do it tomorrow.
PAUL: For now, only that, quadrant setup, and that, landsmith
PAUL: things keep it in here. That's a thing for now. Nothing more.
PAUL: On that unique part.
Amit Singh: Got you, also, yeah. Thank you. Thank you so much. I'll be…
PAUL: Okay, yes.
PAUL: Yes, Mantaj, Aryan, yes, Mantaj, please go ahead. Yes, yes, yes, Mantage.
Mantaaj: Paul, similar question, what other folks have asked, right, regarding…
Mantaaj: the people who are 15 plus years of experience. So, I heard what you have told, right? So, my only question is that
Mantaaj: to RVRS at your level in this…
Mantaaj: organization, are you guys planning to have some…
Mantaaj: Upcoming codes for a system design where…
Mantaaj: it will be more of all MLOps or LLM Ops concept, which you're going to, teach…
Mantaaj: To, to persons who have, 15 plus of your experience.
PAUL: Alright, right now, see, really, like, we have only planned for the first quarter. The first quarter, I know that data science batch, which has been launched, it will start.
PAUL: And the other call that I've taken, it's based on BLMs, vision transformers.
PAUL: That part I have planned. Okay, because for this particular planning, I need inputs from people, so let me connect with few other people then only. Because at least for a batch, there is a minimum threshold that we take it.
PAUL: how many people are interested, little bit of numbers that we need. Once we have that particular information, then I can see, like, previously we have tossed everything separately. MLOps separate is there. LLMOps separate is there. But really, we have not combined.
PAUL: Okay, and generally in this ops part, we never take engineering.
PAUL: Okay, so data engineering part, we don't focus directly much more, because right now, even with respect to the ops part in this project, also, you will get an idea.
PAUL: Because a very similar tech stack, because I feel it doesn't matter which programming language. I'll be building APIs, okay? Those APIs, I'll be performing containerization. Now, after containerization, I'll be deploying them.
PAUL: Okay, so for now, initially, we'll start with monolithic, then probably we can move to microservices.
PAUL: That we can do it. That, from this course, also, you will understand the tech stack, but again, not for ML. ML, it's a little bit different. That's why a few things are different. So, right now, we have not planned it. Let's…
PAUL: Because probably next year, then, we'll be doing a survey. After the survey, only that, we can decide.
Mantaaj: Got it, got it. The whole part is Paul here, just because
Mantaaj: Whatever we are learning from you and from other team members from your…
Mantaaj: organization, right? That is… that is…
Mantaaj: fine, that is good, right? But my only question is that I have around 18 years of experience now.
Mantaaj: Now, if I'm looking for a change, right? So, if they ask me about the system design, right? So, the designing will also come if I would have worked on all those things practically, correct?
PAUL: Got your point. The idea is that pros and cons, and it's basically the struggle, the main thing, why you are switching from this component to this component, why this tech to this tech.
PAUL: Got it. It will come with experience, I got your point.
Mantaaj: Right, so… Okay, we'll, we'll wait.
PAUL: See, like, after this course, okay, like, probably for RAC only, okay, I will share a few designs, okay, which are very specific, only for RAG, that we do for… that I can do after this course, because really, like, with respect to data ingestion.
PAUL: Okay, like, Daxter is there, Prefect is there, I feel, really, they are go-to. But really, like, that is not core RAG component.
PAUL: So, but I will let you know that, okay, at least for RAG, data engineering, these are the possible pipelines that can be built. I will give you an over, high-level system design from RAG perspective.
Mantaaj: That would be great, Paul.
PAUL: And keep this bookmarked, because even I might forget, just after 2 months, give me a reminder, something like that, for everyone I am telling, because I might forget for a few of these things, so always give me a reminder. So, based on that, I will prepare, a few, because they are only no coding, it's only about designs. I will just…
PAUL: draw multiple architectures, and I will tell you that, okay, now these are common standards. For RAG, those standards have been pretty much defined in 2024.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So it's pretty much implementing right now. So, yes, I'll be talking from the RAG perspective, for sure.
Mantaaj: Yeah, no, that should be all true.
Naga: I have a question, Naga here.
PAUL: Wait, wait, wait, I think others are there, Armani, yes. Your question is simply the error. Try to fix it all the time. No, no, no, no, no.
Naga: Not that one. I have this, I installed a data parser.
Naga: So, DataVarser is there, and then RAGQA project, okay? In rag QA project, I cloned this.
Naga: And I… I have this config file here, okay? You can see the open API key is string, and quadrant is string, and this is string, and in the environment, I have put the values, okay? All this one.
Naga: Okay, and that's it, right? Anything else to do for…
PAUL: Nothing, nothing, nothing, nothing, nothing. And going forward, please use an ID, like VS Code or something, because projects, you cannot work in this way. You need a proper ID. Without an ID…
Naga: doing a Jupyter Notebook, actually, right now, so do you think.
PAUL: You cannot do in Jupyter Notebook. You need proper IDE, install something like PyCharm, VS Code, so many editors are there. Anti-gravity, please take that part.
Naga: Yeah, VS Code I will take, because you're absolutely not.
PAUL: Next, Armani.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Yeah, hi, thanks. Actually, the content is really very good, okay? But again, I'm the Ragan, and I don't want to repeat the same thing, because others have very elaborately said it.
PAUL: Yeah, yeah.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: So, but coming down to this one, right, my question is more on, what you can say.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: I've been working as a solution architect and, interface architect, okay, in a bank.
PAUL: Alright.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Now, I wanted to see if I want to solutionize a LLM, okay? One is, I also need to have one hands-on, okay? Majorly, we use on Google, okay? And what things I have to do, get onto more hands-on, or some GitHubs that you want me to practice, okay? And the readings.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: And the second thing I wanted to know is on the system design perspective, if you have anything which can leverage, because one is, when we pass the document, we should not be doing a repeated passing of the documents. Those questions, I have a lot, like, like I say, we have
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Word document. So, once a prompt comes in, I should not repeat the same document parsing. How do I filter out
Armani, Bhagwan Das: the document so that it can go directly into LLM, okay? And, how do I optimize my, what you can say, different, different, parsing, like, docklings versus LAMA? What you can say, today we discussed is, LAMA, right? Llama Index.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Because, see, some things I don't want to send it to the source for a specific reason, not to send it to the Lama Index. Do we have any framework within that, the whole stack?
Armani, Bhagwan Das: to orchestrate these flows. Otherwise, we have to do a manual coding or custom.
PAUL: Till now, there is… nobody has done it, okay? Because this is an initiative that needs to be taken by somebody, okay, probably building a hybrid
PAUL: parser, where you have all the good things of Docklings, all the good things of unstructured, good things from different parsing part and based on that. It's something, like, nobody has taken that initiative and built in such a…
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Good. Okay, but how do we… I mean, how do I enhance my system design perspective on, what you can say,
Armani, Bhagwan Das: or GitHub's to practice more, basically. See, we are lizarding it, but unless… until I solve the problems, my hands will not be tough. My solutions will not be tough, you know, foolproof.
PAUL: So, very specifically, for example, for any design that you were thinking about, pick up a component.
PAUL: And try to, because every component will be optimized to a certain extent, where it can be done.
PAUL: Okay, so we have to pick up component and components. Each component, try to focus. For example, right now, in… right now in this course, we are just focused on the data ingestion pipeline.
PAUL: Okay, now from project 3, I'll be coming into batch processing, async processing. Those are the actual level of optimizations. Okay, because right now we are just reading one stuff. That is nothing. But probably, I think, from our next to next project, somewhere we'll start working with batch and async.
PAUL: Now, that is one level of, I guess, optimization that needs to be done. But again, you need to look into the rate limit for a particular API, and based on that, you have to… otherwise, you have to apply some type of sleep operation for multiple API calls, and that we have to design. So, really, it depends upon
PAUL: The third-party service also to which I'm sending the data, and how much it can take it to launch it.
PAUL: Similar for vector demosolves.
PAUL: Okay, at every point of time, I'll be talking about optimization, but optimizations will come probably after 1 month or 2 months.
PAUL: First, the basics, that everybody is familiar.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: My question is not about optimization. How do they solve multiple different scenarios? Like, if you see simple AI ML, we have a KGL. Okay, so we have anything else that to practice the Jemi, RAC stuff, and all that?
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Victoria.
PAUL: there is no such thing. Kaggle is a platform where you have data sets, and people provide their solutions. As simple as that. Kaggle is nothing, really. Like, I'm not a Kegel fan, but I feel that, okay, for learners or for beginners, it's good.
PAUL: But other than that, once you switch to proper machine learning, deep learning, LLM stuff.
PAUL: Then, really, like, Kaggle, there is, I cannot say there is a single place where you go and get everything.
PAUL: 10 now, like, nobody can build so many courses also, it's very hard. Even for me, I… there are so many aspects
PAUL: Of AI. Okay, that means that every aspect is very hard for everyone to cover.
PAUL: So, in your case, I will suggest, as you have higher years of experience, okay, focus on, very specific, like, Gen AI design systems. You cannot get the topic, but you have to understand the main derivation comes from image system design. Only 30-40% things that will change. Similarly for LEMs.
PAUL: The core part, I can say, in every programming language, the package and shipping part is pretty much the same. Only that core implementation part, that will be pretty much different. And you need to look into when you try to make the solution scalable.
PAUL: Then, actually, what are the services that are needed? So, probably through a cloud, or by introducing Kates, how you are planning to do… that part is very, very important. In the interview, anybody senior, the core idea is how to build or handle a scalable product.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Yeah, yeah. So, I mean, from a cloud standpoint, I can pretty much design right from zero down to the, what do you say, highly scalable applications, okay? But only my question is, from GMAI, how do I scale it up?
PAUL: Genera, it totally depends upon the packaging, how you have done the package of your core application. Once is there, really, see, if I have built some application, and for example, for Scaling, let's take… I'm using, Fargate.
PAUL: If I'm using Farget, I know that automatically it will handle. Exactly. I really do… okay, I don't need to take care of. But again, like, most of my solutions runs on EKs and Fargate. I can say that using EK is very costly, as compared to using… not, Fargate.
PAUL: I feel that, so most of my clients, I say that, please go ahead with Market. But in some cases, if there are specific requirements, because Kubernetes is good, but EKS charges a lot. In that case, bringing a SRE guy, setting up a proper infa.
PAUL: our own Kubernetes. We prefer, then, those type of solutions.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay, because in long-term prospect, it will be cheaper.
PAUL: But in short term, these services actually help you to scale up. You really don't need to do anything. You need to just look into your engineix, how many…
PAUL: request it can handle based on that, apply a load balancer. These are pretty much component stuff. You can always bring and play out, because your core application really doesn't change.
PAUL: Few things, like, after introducing those things, in application level, like I said, really, like, 10-15% changes can be there.
PAUL: Based on scale. Probably you might introduce some type of queue management system through RabbitMQ and others. So, those things comes into the picture.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Got you. So, got you. And one more is… one last question. See, let us say we have built a solution, okay, and I deployed it and forget, okay? I pretty much used to forget, okay? So, how do I maintain a session between, let us say, you are chatting with the system and I am also chatting, how do I maintain that session as a Zoom session type of thing?
PAUL: Session Management.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: session management. I mean, the context, it has to be maintained, right? Like, what you have asked previously.
PAUL: Now, the question comes how you are saving the context.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Yeah, exactly.
PAUL: Whether it's in short-term memory, whether it's in long-term memory, long-term memory, probably SQLite will be used. Okay, now, based on that, so generally what happens across the sessions, you will be using that long-term memory, and long-term memory will be saving all the conversations for that particular user.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Right.
PAUL: later on during the conversation time, you will actually perform some type of comparison, like, for all the chats, a context compression type of functionality that you will add, and that particular information with the new chat, you will send it to the LN.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, if you're using any LLM, you will be sending that, and most of the times, there will be some type of LE. So, in… in that way, you always do the conversation.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay. Do you have any article, or a book, or a video relating to this?
PAUL: No, I don't think so. In this batch, I'll be talking about memory.
PAUL: contextual rag when I were talking.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: intersect, maybe from a YouTube or a medium or…
PAUL: See, really, like, with respect to memory, there are a few things in Lansion that you can look into. Otherwise, for agent EQS frameworks, once we start there, in every framework, they do have a memory definition.
PAUL: Okay, like, long-term memory, short-term memory, long, short memory, different type. Or very specifically, if you want to use some type of third-party service, there are two major services. One is Mem, mem0.ai. It is widely used, okay, whether for agents and others.
PAUL: Then the other one is, Memory. M-O, M-E-M-O-R-I, from Gibson Labs. Gibson EI Labs. These two are very famous products.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Can you spell the name? Gypsum.
PAUL: Gibson, just search for memory Gibson, you will get it in GitHub.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: It eats and laps, okay.
PAUL: Gibson Labs, that one.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay, got you. Okay.
PAUL: Generally, using this, you can take your implementation to the next level. So if you directly explore this, you will see that everybody has an integration with Llama Index or Lansion.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay, got you.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay, yeah.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Thanks a lot.
PAUL: Okay.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: So, again, a lot of questions, open questions were there, so today I get…
PAUL: You can make a list of the questions and set them in a minute or so.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: me and say.
PAUL: Many people have.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: get a response. I sent a follow-up mail. I got a response. I sent a follow-up mail, but I did not get it back, one of the use cases that I am working on with, actually, so…
PAUL: You see, if you're dropping me, at least you can let me know, because I know others have dropped, I've responded.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Yeah. Just be sure you drop me sometimes, or otherwise add just a reminder somewhere.
PAUL: Generally, I do it by Friday, because, say, open-ended question, many students ask. Anything.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Okay, so, yes, do a simple, like, record it somewhere, convert into text, and send it to me.
Armani, Bhagwan Das: Sure.
PAUL: Eyeballs. Next. E-S-R-E.
Aaryan Gupta: So I have a career-related question, not a technical one, but directly related to this course.
Aaryan Gupta: So, please allow me to give a little background of myself. I have 3.5 years of experience as an analyst.
Aaryan Gupta: And, but I don't… have, on… hands-on knowledge, practice on ML systems.
Aaryan Gupta: industry experience on ML systems. But now, I have been trying to transition myself and upscaling myself to either go into a field of, like, ML engineer, and I'm a bit confused between what to choose, like, since there are a variety of fields, like ML engineer and NLP engineer.
Aaryan Gupta: And, this, rag…
Aaryan Gupta: engineer, basically. So, as per the market demand and scope, I am trying to figure out what shall I do next, as I have built one ML system as well, which I can showcase in my interview, but I'm not sure if I can…
Aaryan Gupta: build a rack system as of now, and showcase in the interview, since they all required LLMs and quite amount, quite some amount of expense.
Aaryan Gupta: And I'm not sure how to build a rag as of now, since companies are also required to have, people to have certain projects with them.
Aaryan Gupta: But as per my market, as per the market demand, I think I should be moving towards RAG, but…
Aaryan Gupta: since I have practiced, and made system on ML system,
Aaryan Gupta: I think moving towards ML engineer should be the best thing, but…
PAUL: In the market, very less hiring is going for ML engineers. That's the main thing. In 2025,
PAUL: the number of rules are really towards the lower side. As I feed back, it was…
PAUL: 3 years, 4 years back.
PAUL: Right now, Gen AI is much more towards the train, but yes, there are a few. Because in machine learning, you have to be very good in stats.
PAUL: That's the main thing, for machine learning roles. Whereas in Gen AI, if you are not good in stats, then also it is fine.
PAUL: Okay. At least that basic level of stats helps you, but in machine learning, you have to be very good in stats.
PAUL: Because usually, in organization, a lot of, like, statistical tests, probabilistic tests, fantastic tests, so many testing that comes around with machine learning.
Aaryan Gupta: Is it same in data centers as well?
PAUL: Yes, data scientists also. Nobody teaches those things. When you go in the organization, directly people will say, in two short forms, do this, do this.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay.
Aaryan Gupta: So, with this course which you are teaching right now, and we will be doing some projects, will that be able to help me, to crack the interviews? Like…
PAUL: For interview cracking, you need a proper… it means that somebody will ask you in your previous organization, what have you done? Now, that part, I am teaching you one part, but I am not telling you that project. Now, that particular thing, what type of problem statement based on your organization.
PAUL: domain that you have selected. It can be a, like, from POC, you have moved it to an MVP phase, from MVP from… to the next phase. Okay, so in that way, you can say that. So, but actually, what is the story? What is the amount of data, volume, so many things that comes.
PAUL: So, exactly, your storytelling skills, that matters.
Aaryan Gupta: So, is it applicable for the entry-level person as well?
PAUL: No, if somebody's a fresher, not a lot of expectation. Really, anybody less than 3 years, I won't say my expectation will be high. My expectation will be no fundamentals. You should know one programming language. You should know one database and one thing.
PAUL: Bad minimum.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay, okay, so it's suitable for me, since I have an analyst background, but not in, this NLP and REG, so it's suitable for me, this course, right? And…
Aaryan Gupta: So that was my major question, like, what I should be pursuing, since there are a variety of fields, like NLP engineer or RAG-based engineer. That was the main thing.
Aaryan Gupta: Okay.
PAUL: focused on… because right now, I've seen the Gen AI rules are much more towards the right side in India as compared to LLMs, because building LLMs is not, I guess, a very costly solution. So, majorly in Indian market, I have seen RAG-based role.coms. They have proprietary internal data. On top of that, they might want to build some type of system.
PAUL: Okay.
Aaryan Gupta: Open food.
Aaryan Gupta: Thank you.
PAUL: moderate.
PAUL: Okay… See ya.
Naga: Bye.
PAUL: Yes. Go ahead.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Yeah,
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Actually, I was facing the problem, earlier I was mentioned in the chart, related to the region. Actually, when I'm trying to execute, then it's, giving the,
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: tick mark, but, it's giving API color based on the region.
PAUL: The agent show me, show me, really, like, because in today's class, there is nothing with respect to the region that I've discussed.
PAUL: So, tell me.
PAUL: You can start sharing your screen.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Indeed.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: I'm trying to execute this.
PAUL: It's any invalid API key. Please pass the correct API key.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: I, I, I, actually, I took, carctuan only, just,
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Invalid key, and it's mentioned here.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Please check your region.
PAUL: developers click on that link, developers.lamaIndex. Generally, with respect to regions, I am not… Faced any issues?
PAUL: North America, Europe, this is fine. The Europe is costlier as compared to North America.
PAUL: Okay, Llama Cloud… Because if I look into the base URL by default, Let's get initialized.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Oh.
PAUL: I'm doing well.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Europe.
PAUL: It doesn't matter, because the base URL, they are changing it.
PAUL: And the initialization of Lama Path.
PAUL: Alright, the base URL is getting changed. Now, see, that llama parse, when we are calling, okay, in that llama parse, check for the arguments, and probably you can pass a custom base URL.
PAUL: Where you are calling, yes, the first part initially. Okay, so in Lama Pass, check that, do you have that
PAUL: argument of changing, the base URL.
PAUL: Okay, and copy-paste me that error in chat, and let me just look into it.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Nope.
PAUL: Just let me copy-paste that error in the chat that you were getting.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Okay. That region change.
PAUL: Nope.
PAUL: Copy-paste that entire thing.
PAUL: Scroll below, huh, that error copy.
PAUL: And paste it, let me see.
PAUL: In chat, drop it.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Alright.
PAUL: Open your… Zoom chat, and pasting, please.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Actually, it's, it's…
PAUL: Just stop sharing, and then paste it, yeah.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Yeah, yeah, I will do it now.
PAUL: Alright, quarter one.
PAUL: Let me see in some places with respect to…
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Oh my gosh, how am I with you?
PAUL: Tune me your, .env file once.
PAUL: Have you changed the variable name in email?
PAUL: Because this part Llama Cloud key…
PAUL: Alright, this looks good,
PAUL: My OpenAI key is equal to, like, the documents I got in a cheat sheet, the API key is equal to Lama Cloud API key.
PAUL: It's telling that on March 8, it's because it does not work with Lamakao Europe region, you need to change this.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Okay, then what I need to select?
PAUL: I'm looking into, like, right now, the troubleshoot.
PAUL: Because directly selecting the region, I'm just changing, like, where this particular parameter is available.
PAUL: Okay, so that you can change the base URL.
PAUL: I think that the base URL…
PAUL: that is getting invoked is that European one. In Europe, few features are not supported.
PAUL: In North America, all the features are supported.
PAUL: Because region, during the API key creation, did you…
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: not asking.
PAUL: Okay, yes, that's the part it doesn't ask only, so I'm thinking about how you pay C1L
PAUL: Yeah, sticking to that one. Just wait.
PAUL: Yeah, you were just telling, check your API key, check your… because other operations are working, only this operation is failing.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Yeah.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Other operations are everything is working fine.
PAUL: Because here you have, there is no such complexity here, I'm not using any…
PAUL: Specialized LAMA path, verbose, PDF path exists, load data, and finally, we're printing the data.
PAUL: So from where it pre-picked up, Okay…
PAUL: Lana Park docs I need to really look into.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Hmm.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Oh, yeah, I love the villain.
PAUL: Okay, so one thing you can do… So I'm sharing…
PAUL: one piece of food, okay? Can you please say that?
PAUL: Because the default URL is fine.
PAUL: In chat, I am sharing to try to have a look into this.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Okay, I will look, and I will modify. I can tell you this.
PAUL: Change the base URL. The base URL is this one that I'm sharing here.
PAUL: You too.
PAUL: API Cloud, there won't be any events, so try to change that one.
PAUL: In the chat, I have shared it.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Okay, you… U under, base underscore URL.
PAUL: Check with the… there are two regions only, the EU and the North. The… the one mentioned within EU is very specific to the EU region.
PAUL: And the other one, it is for the North American region.
PAUL: Okay, so by changing this…
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: go… Yeah, if I go to this URL and I need to create API key…
PAUL: You don't need to create an API, the same API should work.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Okay, then where I need to… okay.
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: I will put…
PAUL: The LamaParse function, there you need to change and you need to test it, okay?
Srinivasa Rao Tadela: Okay, okay, okay, thank you.
PAUL: One big…
PAUL: Okay, alright. Armani, your hand is raised, yes.
PAUL: Money and negotiations.
PAUL: Okay, looks like no response. All right, guys, so tomorrow we will start the project. Please don't miss the classes. The next week is very important.
PAUL: Okay, so at least, I think, 3 classes that we might spend, or probably 4.
PAUL: Okay? Nava, if you have questions, simply raise your hand, I can take it.
PAUL: So please don't miss the classes. If somebody misses these project classes, in the second project, it will be very painful.
PAUL: Because my idea is that I will explain once, okay, in a single project, everything. You can ask twice, thrice, four times, but at least in second project, the same question, please don't ask. Okay, so spend more time. In the first project, I can spend four days, probably 2 weeks.
PAUL: Okay, so please spend more time from your side.
PAUL: Yes, Naga, tell me.
Naga: No, no, I need to share my screen, that's all.
PAUL: Okay, then, promote to panelists, I have done it. Mohamed, yes, Monet.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Hey, Paul, can you hear me?
PAUL: Yes, yes.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Okay, so, okay, first of all, sorry about the misunderstanding. I didn't mean you, I meant the…
PAUL: I got it, I got it. Yeah. Okay, but actually, your training.
Muhanned Alogaidi: I mean, remove any doubts that I faced, and that's really thanks to you. So, okay, I have a few shorter questions. The first one, for the project tomorrow, do you plan to provide the instructions for the setup, in case of anyone missed something, or in the future we need to go back to the project?
PAUL: Setup means, like, from scratch. Today, only two things that I told, ENV variable, set that. Tomorrow, like, I'll be creating the virtual environment. Everything from scratch only I'll be doing. All the files will be there. It will be a blank folder. From that blank folder, we will bring it to that GitHub structure.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Great, because usually, I mean, let's say now it's 3 AM in my time, so typically after that time, we'll not install or do anything, but just want to check this one. So, okay.
Muhanned Alogaidi: I noticed through this cohort that we're missing a few things, like transformers, principles, LLM, or, I mean, regenerative AI. So, can you please just refer us to any, like, I mean, videos from the same academy, or, I mean, papers, so we can just, I mean.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Refresher on quantum.
PAUL: Yes, drop me a mail, like, for Transformers, I'll be sharing you the best resources.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Amazing.
PAUL: those are the best in the market, I'll be sharing a few YouTube videos, few blogs. From there, you will get an idea. A very good idea, I can say.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Thank you so much. So, okay, my third question about this cohort. Are you planning to provide additional real-world projects like those will help us in the industry that's, I mean, let's say, manage real-world problems, even this one, or separated and related to RAG?
PAUL: It will be much more RAG-focused.
PAUL: Right now, really, like, I'll be working much more on components and design. The idea is that you bring your own data, you plug and play.
PAUL: Because, really, on data, I don't want to be very specific.
PAUL: My idea is that building robots, like, from step 1 to step 2 till step 3, step 4, step 3 and 4 are really, like, very complex.
PAUL: Okay, it will take a lot of time, but it's majorly on RAM.
PAUL: I am not focused towards data so much.
Muhanned Alogaidi: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, Naga, you are sharing, so…
Naga: Yeah, I had a question. I have, actually, installed, like, I…
Naga: Activated this environment, okay? And then installed all the requirements.
Naga: For the tomorrow.
Naga: So, how do I change to that, environment? Actually, I created one, virtual environment, like Rajuv here, and how do I change to that?
PAUL: How do I change to that?
Naga: I have to, like, the right side, you'll have the, like, some environment name, right? VNV, something like here, but how do I get that?
PAUL: from VNV, you won't be getting, I don't think, because it happens in Jupyter Notebook, where you get the option to select a kernel. Now, where is your VNV folder? Here?
PAUL: This is a new folder, this is…
Naga: This is Raja Foder, yeah. This is where I created the entire, in the… I did the installation, and…
Naga: Just, I think it's still installing, but, here, here I'm in that environment, yeah.
Naga: It's still installing something.
PAUL: Okay, fine. So, right now, the environment selection creates a BNV in the current workspace. You don't need this. Conda, create a .conda environment, and this was optional, so you don't need.
Naga: I already activated that, Raju environment.
PAUL: how you have activated. You have done from it from the terminal, no? Yeah, from terminal, correct. From terminal, I did activate. But in ID, how you are going to use it?
Naga: Yeah, that's what I'm asking, actually, like, how do I select the environment, or something like that.
PAUL: Generally, whenever we are executing, just click on that Python file. Below, we get the options, like, where Python 3.13 is written.
PAUL: Bottom right. Bottom right.
Naga: Yes, it's already.
PAUL: Okay, click on that.
Naga: Yes, it's…
PAUL: This is… from here, you select which environment you want to use.
PAUL: click on Python 3.13 Rajun.
PAUL: That's…
Naga: Sective.
Naga: Oh, okay. And, now, like, Jupyter Notebook, I have to execute, like, for example, how do I execute those? Like, for example, let's say…
PAUL: If you… there is no Jupyter notebook here. If you have a Jupyter notebook, you have to select the same environment kernel done.
Naga: No, no, but how do I run this? Like, for example, like, just run, run this?
PAUL: when I will show you in tomorrow's class how to run, you don't need, because.
Naga: Because it is going into the PowerShell, basically, right now.
PAUL: With respect to execution, tomorrow I will show you.
PAUL: Okay. If you're executing, you'll be writing Python, the name of the script. Done.
Naga: Okay.
Naga: Here in the comment prompt, right, you're saying? Okay.
PAUL: from the terminal.
PAUL: I'll be using it from the terminal. I don't know, like, tomorrow, if I'm going with PyChump, then only I do it execute, but in other things, it will be from terminal.
Naga: Direction… dot P1.
PAUL: Okay, so spend some time, because tomorrow don't come that I'm issued the environment. Environment, everything I have shared. Okay, tomorrow then directly we can start with the project part.
PAUL: Alright, fine then.
Naga: I think we are done.
PAUL: I'll be concluding the session for today. Everyone, let's meet tomorrow and start our first project.
PAUL: Bye, everyone. Thanks for joining.
Naga: It's not my lovely.